<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>resumable-upload on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/resumable-upload/</link>
    <description>Recent content in resumable-upload on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:34:46 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/resumable-upload/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curl Command Uploading Video File to YouTube with Resumable Upload using YouTube API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/11/11/curl-command-uploading-video-file-to-youtube-with-resumable-upload-using-youtube-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 21:34:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/11/11/curl-command-uploading-video-file-to-youtube-with-resumable-upload-using-youtube-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample curl command for uploading a video file to YouTube with the resumable upload using YouTube API.
In order to upload a video file to YouTube with the resumable upload using YouTube API, the following 2 processes are required to be done.
In this sample curl command, your access token can be used for uploading a file to YouTube. Please be careful about this.
1. Retrieve the location URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Script for Resumable Upload to Google Drive using Axios with Node.js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/08/07/sample-script-for-resumable-upload-to-google-drive-using-axios-with-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 09:26:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/08/07/sample-script-for-resumable-upload-to-google-drive-using-axios-with-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for the resumable upload using Axios with Node.js.
Sample script In this sample script, as a sample situation in order to explain the resumable upload, the file data is loaded from the local PC, and the data is uploaded to Google Drive with the resumable upload.
const axios = require(&amp;#34;axios&amp;#34;); const fs = require(&amp;#34;fs&amp;#34;).promises;  async function sample() {  const filepath = &amp;#34;./###&amp;#34;; // Please set the filename and file path of the upload file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: Javascript library - ResumableUploadForGoogleDrive_js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/11/15/updated-javascript-library-resumableuploadforgoogledrive_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 15:38:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/11/15/updated-javascript-library-resumableuploadforgoogledrive_js/</guid>
      <description>ResumableUploadForGoogleDrive_js was updated to v2.0.0.
  v2.0.0 (November 15, 2021)
 New Class ResumableUploadToGoogleDrive2 was added. By this, the large file which is over the memory in the local PC can be uploaded by the resumable upload.    Overview This is a Javascript library to achieve the resumable upload for Google Drive.
Description When a file more than 5 MB is uploaded to Google Drive with Drive API, the resumable upload is required to be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Script of Resumable Upload with Google Drive API for Axios</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/01/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-axios/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:18:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/01/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-axios/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a simple sample script for achieving the resumable upload to Google Drive using Axios. In order to achieve the resumable upload, at first, it is required to retrieve the location, which is the endpoint of upload. The location is included in the response headers. After the location was retrieved, the file can be uploaded to the location URL.
In this sample, a text data is uploaded with the resumable upload using a single chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading and Uploading File to Google Drive without Saving File with Stream and Resumable Upload using Node.js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/01/05/downloading-and-uploading-file-to-google-drive-without-saving-file-with-stream-and-resumable-upload-using-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 15:38:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/01/05/downloading-and-uploading-file-to-google-drive-without-saving-file-with-stream-and-resumable-upload-using-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script of Node.js for downloading the data and uploading the data to Google Drive with the resumable upload without saving it as a file. The downloaded data is uploaded to Google Drive with the stream.
Sample script Before you use this, please set the variables of accessToken, url, fileSize, mimeType and filename. In this case, fileSize is required to set because the data is uploaded with the resumable upload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating a File with Resumable Upload using Drive API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/04/20/updating-a-file-with-resumable-upload-using-drive-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:41:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/04/20/updating-a-file-with-resumable-upload-using-drive-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample flow for updating a file with the resumable upload using Drive API.
Sample situation: In this answer, as a sample situation, it supposes that a text file in Google Drive is updated by the resumable upload with the multiple chunks. And as the method for requesting, I use the curl command.
I prepared 2 files for 2 chunks. As the test situation, the 2 chunks of 262,144 bytes and 37,856 bytes are uploaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Script of Resumable Upload with Google Drive API for Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:10:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a simple sample script for achieving the resumable upload to Google Drive using Python. In order to achieve the resumable upload, at first, it is required to retrieve the location, which is the endpoint of upload. The location is included in the response headers. After the location was retrieved, the file can be uploaded to the location URL.
In this sample, a PNG file is uploaded with the resumable upload using a single chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Script of Resumable Upload with Google Drive API for Node.js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 13:48:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a simple sample script for achieving the resumable upload to Google Drive using Node.js. In order to achieve the resumable upload, at first, it is required to retrieve the location, which is the endpoint of upload. The location is included in the response headers. After the location was retrieved, the file can be uploaded to the location URL.
In this sample, a PNG file is uploaded with the resumable upload using a single chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Upload of Multiple Files with Asynchronous Process for Google Drive</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/14/resumable-upload-of-multiple-files-with-asynchronous-process-for-google-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 11:06:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/14/resumable-upload-of-multiple-files-with-asynchronous-process-for-google-drive/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a sample script for uploading multiple files with large size (&amp;gt; 50 MB) at the sidebar, dialog of Google Docs and Web Apps using the resumable upload of the asynchronous process with Javascript and Google Apps Script (GAS).
Demo This is a demonstration of this script. As a demonstration, it uploads 5 files with the size of 100 MB to own Google Drive. When the files were selected and the upload button is clicked, those are uploaded by the resumable upload with the asynchronous process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript library - ResumableUploadForGoogleDrive_js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/11/javascript-library-resumableuploadforgoogledrive_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 13:07:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/11/javascript-library-resumableuploadforgoogledrive_js/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a Javascript library to achieve the resumable upload for Google Drive.
Description When a file more than 5 MB is uploaded to Google Drive with Drive API, the resumable upload is required to be used. I have already published the sample script for &amp;ldquo;Resumable Upload for Web Apps using Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo;. Ref In this case, Web Apps is used. Here, I would like to introduce the script for the resumable upload created by only Javascript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Upload for Web Apps using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/17/resumable-upload-for-web-apps-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 16:48:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/17/resumable-upload-for-web-apps-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>News   At October 11, 2019, I published a Javascript library to to run the resumable upload for Google Drive. When this is used, the large file can be uploaded. You can also use this js library.
 Resumable Upload of Multiple Files with Asynchronous Process for Google Drive    Overview This is a sample script for uploading files with large size (&amp;gt; 50 MB) at Web Apps using Google Apps Script (GAS).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
