<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>search on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/search/</link>
    <description>Recent content in search on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 15:58:12 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/search/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification of Search Query for File List Method in Drive API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/04/27/specification-of-search-query-for-file-list-method-in-drive-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 15:58:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/04/27/specification-of-search-query-for-file-list-method-in-drive-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
In this report, I would like to report about the current specification of the search query for the file list method in Drive API.
Recently, I noticed that the specification of the search query for the file list method in Drive API might have been changed. I thought that to know the change of specification of the search query is important for creating the application using Drive API. In this report, I would like to introduce the current specification of the search query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completed: Web Application for searching Google Apps Script Library from Database</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/12/completed-web-application-for-searching-google-apps-script-library-from-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 11:58:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/12/completed-web-application-for-searching-google-apps-script-library-from-database/</guid>
      <description>Web Application for searching Google Apps Script Library from Database was completed. So I published it as v1.0.0. Please check Google Apps Script Library Database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - DateFinder</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/30/gas-library-datefinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 13:37:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/30/gas-library-datefinder/</guid>
      <description>Overview DateFinder is a GAS library for searching the date objects from the cell range on the sheet in the Spreadsheet and retrieving the searched range as the RangeList object using Google Apps Script (GAS).
Description There is the Class TextFinder for searching the text from cells of the Spreadsheet using the Google Apps Script. But in this case, the date object in the cell is used as the string. Namely, the values for searching are used as the same with the values retrieved by getDisplayValues().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark: Search for Array Processing using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/02/benchmark-search-for-array-processing-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:55:45 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/02/benchmark-search-for-array-processing-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Benchmark: Search for Array Processing using Google Apps Script Kanshi Tanaike
Introduction Please be careful! This result can be only used for Google Apps Script.
There are a limit executing time for Google Apps Script (GAS). That is 6 minutes.1 So users always have to pay attention to reducing the process cost of the scripts. Especially, it is very important to know the process cost for the array processing, because the array processing is often used for spreadsheet and Google APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - goris</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/26/cli-tool-goris/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 16:52:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/26/cli-tool-goris/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to search for images with Google Reverse Image Search.
Motivation Because I had wanted to search for images with an image URL and file on my terminal, I created this. This can download images from searched image URLs.
**The detail information and how to get this are https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>