<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruby on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruby on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 16:04:18 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sample Scripts for Creating New Event with Google Meet Link to Google Calendar using Various Languages</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 16:04:18 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages. When I saw the official document of &amp;ldquo;Add video and phone conferences to events&amp;rdquo;, in the current stage, I can see only the sample script for Javascript. But I saw the several questions related to this for various languages. So I published the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - SOUWA_GAS - Effects on Optimized Codes of Pyramid Method</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</guid>
      <description>Abstract I have already reported that the pyramid method is one of very effectively algolithms for summing string elements in an array using Google Apps Script (GAS). This report describes the adaptability of the pyramid method to any languages except for GAS. c++ (g++), Go, Java, Javascript on Node.js, Python and Ruby were chosen as the sample languages. In those languages, there are languages which have the distinctive commands for summing the array elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
