<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:03:26 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification of Files: copy in Drive API was changed</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/07/09/specification-of-files-copy-in-drive-api-was-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 17:03:26 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/07/09/specification-of-files-copy-in-drive-api-was-changed/</guid>
      <description>I noticed that the specification of Files: copy in Drive API was changed. About the method of Files: copy in Drive API v3, this method could be used with the scope of https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive.readonly until July 5, 2020. But I confirmed that in the current stage, the scope is required to be changed to the following scopes.
 https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive.file https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive.appdata https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive.photos.readonly  Please be careful this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer of owner of files got not to be able to be used with batch requests of Drive API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/07/07/transfer-of-owner-of-files-got-not-to-be-able-to-be-used-with-batch-requests-of-drive-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 13:31:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/07/07/transfer-of-owner-of-files-got-not-to-be-able-to-be-used-with-batch-requests-of-drive-api/</guid>
      <description>At 15, June 2020, I have reported the transfer of owner of files got to be able to be achieved with batch requests of Drive API. Ref And also, yesterday (06, July 2020), I could have confirmed that this could be worked. But, now (07, July 2020), the following response is returned.
{&amp;#34;error&amp;#34;: {&amp;#34;errors&amp;#34;: [{&amp;#34;domain&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;global&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;reason&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;invalidSharingRequest&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;message&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Bad Request. User message: \&amp;#34;You can&amp;#39;t yet change the owner of this item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transfer of owner of files got to be able to be achieved with batch requests of Drive API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/15/transfer-of-owner-of-files-got-to-be-able-to-be-achieved-with-batch-requests-of-drive-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 14:37:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/15/transfer-of-owner-of-files-got-to-be-able-to-be-achieved-with-batch-requests-of-drive-api/</guid>
      <description>Today, I could confirm that the transfer of owner of files got to be able to be achieved with batch requests of Drive API. When I had tested this at January 31, 2020, an error of there is no function to change the owner of this item yet (currently under development) had occurred.
But today, I could confirm that this got to be able to be achieved by the batch requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Shared Drive using Drive Service of Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/02/managing-shared-drive-using-drive-service-of-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 20:42:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/02/managing-shared-drive-using-drive-service-of-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
When the method of &amp;ldquo;Files: list&amp;rdquo; in Drive API v3, the official document of includeItemsFromAllDrives and supportsAllDrives says as follows.
 Deprecated - Whether both My Drive and shared drive items should be included in results. This parameter will only be effective until June 1, 2020. Afterwards shared drive items are included in the results. (Default: false)
  Deprecated - Whether the requesting application supports both My Drives and shared drives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive API cannot create Google Apps Script project no longer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/09/drive-api-cannot-create-google-apps-script-project-no-longer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 15:09:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/09/drive-api-cannot-create-google-apps-script-project-no-longer/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Today, I noticed that new Google Apps Script project of the standalone script type cannot be created by the method of Files: create in Drive API. From now, in order to manage the Google Apps Script project, only Google Apps Script API is required to be used. By this, the following issues are brought.
 When the new standalone GAS project is created in the specific folder by uploading the local script, the following flow is required to be run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V8 Runtime was added to Google Apps Script at February 7, 2020</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/02/07/v8-runtime-was-added-to-google-apps-script-at-february-7-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 11:09:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/02/07/v8-runtime-was-added-to-google-apps-script-at-february-7-2020/</guid>
      <description>Gists
In my environment, at February 7, 2020, when I opened the script editor of Google Apps Script, the following notification could be seen.
By this, I could notice that finally, the V8 Runtime has already been added to Google Apps Script. I think that this will be also the great news for a lot of users including me.
The detail of V8 Runtime can be seen at https://developers.google.com/apps-script/guides/v8-runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification of Google Apps Script Project was Changed at April 8, 2019</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/05/16/specification-of-google-apps-script-project-was-changed-at-april-8-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 08:50:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/05/16/specification-of-google-apps-script-project-was-changed-at-april-8-2019/</guid>
      <description>Gists
At April 8, 2019, the specification of Google Apps Script Project was changed. Various specification was changed. Please see the detail at Google Cloud Platform Projects. Here, I would like to introduce one change which might be useful for users. The official document says as follows.
 When you enable an advanced service for your script project in the Apps Script editor, it is automatically enabled in the default GCP project when the script project is saved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>