<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unicode Normalization on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/unicode-normalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unicode Normalization on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 12:41:24 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/unicode-normalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unicode normalization using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/03/16/unicode-normalization-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 12:41:24 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/03/16/unicode-normalization-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a script for converting strings from NFD (Normalization Form Decomposition) to NFC (Normalization Form Composition) using Google Apps Script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here, I would like to introduce a script for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unicode_equivalence#Normal_forms&#34;&gt;the unicode normalization&lt;/a&gt; using Google Apps Script. There are the characters with &lt;code&gt;゙&lt;/code&gt; which is the voiced dot and the characters with &lt;code&gt;゚&lt;/code&gt; which is the semi-voiced dot in Japanese language. When these are used for some applications, there are 2 kinds of usages for the character. For example, when for &lt;code&gt;は&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;\u306f&lt;/code&gt;) HA with the voiced dot, there are &lt;code&gt;ば&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ば&lt;/code&gt;. These unicodes are &lt;code&gt;\u3070&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;\u306f\u3099&lt;/code&gt;. Namely, there are the case which displayed 1 character as 2 characters. In most cases, the characters like &lt;code&gt;\u3070&lt;/code&gt; are used. This called NFC (Normalization Form Composition). But we sometimes meet the characters like &lt;code&gt;\u306f\u3099&lt;/code&gt;. This called NFD (Normalization Form Decomposition). When the document including such characters which are displayed as 2 characters is converted to PDF file, each character is separated like &lt;code&gt;は  ゙&lt;/code&gt;. So users often want to convert the characters constructed by 2 characters to the single characters. Recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Global_Objects/String/normalize&#34;&gt;String.prototype.normalize&lt;/a&gt; was added at ES2015. But ES2015 cannot be used at Google Apps Script yet. And although I had looked for the scripts like this for GAS, unfortunately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find. So I created this script.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
