<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Apps on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/web-apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Apps on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 17:55:14 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/web-apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Functions by Specifying Function Names with Web Apps for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/26/running-functions-by-specifying-function-names-with-web-apps-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 17:55:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/26/running-functions-by-specifying-function-names-with-web-apps-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
In this report, I would like to introduce the method for running functions by directly specifying the function names with Web Apps for Google Apps Script.
Description It has already been known that the directly specified functions in the project can be run from the outside by enabling &amp;ldquo;API executable&amp;rdquo; and using the method of scripts.run in Google Apps Script API. In this case, the installation for using Apps Script API is a bit complicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Cells of Spreadsheet that Users Copied from Your Google Drive to User&#39;s Google Drive using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/17/protecting-cells-of-spreadsheet-that-users-copied-from-your-google-drive-to-users-google-drive-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 08:20:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/17/protecting-cells-of-spreadsheet-that-users-copied-from-your-google-drive-to-users-google-drive-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is the method for protecting cells of Spreadsheet that users copied from your Google Drive to user&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive using Google Apps Script.
Situation: This method supposes the following situation.
 You want to make users copy a Spreadsheet on your Google Drive to user&amp;rsquo;s Google Drive. - Your Spreadsheet has several protected ranges. - Your Spreadsheet is shared with the user. - User doesn&amp;rsquo;t have own folder shared with you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
