<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTML on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/html/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTML on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:32:58 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Expanding Gemini API&#39;s Capabilities: A Practical Solution for Web Content Summarization</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/23/expanding-gemini-apis-capabilities-a-practical-solution-for-web-content-summarization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:32:58 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/23/expanding-gemini-apis-capabilities-a-practical-solution-for-web-content-summarization/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This study proposes a workaround to address the Gemini API&amp;rsquo;s current inability to directly process web content from URLs. By utilizing Google Apps Script, the method extracts relevant information from a specified URL and feeds it into the API for summarization. This approach offers a solution for generating comprehensive summaries from web-based content until the API&amp;rsquo;s limitations are resolved.
Introduction While Gemini API offers powerful text generation capabilities, it currently faces limitations in directly accessing and processing web content from URLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report: Values to transfer between Javascript and Google Apps Script with google.script.run</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/08/28/report-values-to-transfer-between-javascript-and-google-apps-script-with-google.script.run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 10:40:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/08/28/report-values-to-transfer-between-javascript-and-google-apps-script-with-google.script.run/</guid>
      <description>Gists At the Google Apps Script project, the values can be transferred from HTML to Google Apps Script using google.script.run with Javascript. In this case, unfortunately, the values of all types cannot be transferred. In the official document, it says as follows. Ref Most types are legal, but not Date, Function, or DOM element besides form; see description Legal parameters are JavaScript primitives like a Number, Boolean, String, or null,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Google Spreadsheet to HTML Table using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/21/converting-google-spreadsheet-to-html-table-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 14:44:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/21/converting-google-spreadsheet-to-html-table-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for converting Google Spreadsheet to an HTML table using Google Apps Script.
There is the case that it is required to convert a sheet in a Google Spreadsheet to an HTML table. For example, there might be a situation that a sheet in a Google Spreadsheet is sent as an email including an HTML table. And, there might be a situation in which a sheet in a Google Spreadsheet is published to an HTML page including the converted HTML table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue of HTML form with Input tab of Type File with google.script.run</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/15/issue-of-html-form-with-input-tab-of-type-file-with-google.script.run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 21:30:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/15/issue-of-html-form-with-input-tab-of-type-file-with-google.script.run/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Today, I discussed with Riël Notermans an issue with the HTML form with the input tab of type=&amp;quot;file&amp;quot; with google.script.run. Through this discussion, the reason for this issue could be found. When you use the input tab of type=&amp;quot;file&amp;quot; in the HTML form, and you want to send the file content with google.script.run, I thought that this post might be useful for other users. So, I posted it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark: Process cost for HTML Template using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/06/07/benchmark-process-cost-for-html-template-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 11:35:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/06/07/benchmark-process-cost-for-html-template-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Introduction When we use HTML in the Google Apps Script project, in order to show the values from the Google Apps Script side, the HTML template is used. When I used the HTML template with a large value, I understood that the process cost can be reduced by devising a script. In this report, I would like to introduce the process cost of the HTML template using the benchmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simply Converting HTML to Plain Text using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/22/simply-converting-html-to-plain-text-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:21:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/22/simply-converting-html-to-plain-text-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for simply converting HTML to plain text using Google Apps Script.
Sample values HTML (input value) &amp;lt;div id=&amp;#34;sample1&amp;#34;&amp;gt;sample text1&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;#34;sample2&amp;#34;&amp;gt;sample text2&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul id=&amp;#34;sample3&amp;#34;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;sample list 1&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;sample list 2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;table id=&amp;#34;sample4&amp;#34;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;a1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;b1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;c1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;a2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;b2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;c2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/table&amp;gt; Text (output value) sample text1sample text2- sample list 1- sample list 2a1 b1 c1a2 b2 c2 Sample script function myFunction() {  const sampleHTML = `&amp;lt;div id=&amp;#34;sample1&amp;#34;&amp;gt;sample text1&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&amp;#34;sample2&amp;#34;&amp;gt;sample text2&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;ul id=&amp;#34;sample3&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;sample list 1&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;sample list 2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;table id=&amp;#34;sample4&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;a1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;b1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;c1&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;a2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;b2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;c2&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;`;  const temp = GmailApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When &#39;//&#39; in template literal is used in a HTML file in script editor, it is used as a comment start</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/05/10/when-/-in-template-literal-is-used-in-a-html-file-in-script-editor-it-is-used-as-a-comment-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:40:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/05/10/when-/-in-template-literal-is-used-in-a-html-file-in-script-editor-it-is-used-as-a-comment-start/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Overview When // in template literal is used in a HTML file in script editor, it is used as a comment start.
const sample = `//`; For example, when above script is used in a HTML file at the script editor, ;&amp;quot; of const sample =`//`; is used as the comment.
Description I would like to explain about this bug using the following sample flow.
Flow   Create new Spreadsheet and open the script editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parsing HTML using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/01/parsing-html-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 14:04:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/01/parsing-html-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for parsing HTML using Google Apps Script. When HTML data is converted to Google Document, the HTML data can be parsed and be converted to Google Document. In this case, the paragraphs, lists and tables are included. From this situation, I thought that this situation can be used for parsing HTML using Google Apps Script. So I could came up with this method.
In the Sheet API, the HTML data can be put to the Spreadsheet with the PasteDataRequest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting Files in Google Drive using Select Box for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/17/selecting-files-in-google-drive-using-select-box-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 13:26:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/17/selecting-files-in-google-drive-using-select-box-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for selecting files in Google Drive using HTML select box for Google Apps Script.
Feature Feature of this sample.
 It is a simple and space saving. When the folder is selected, the files in the folder are shown. When the file is selected, the ID of file is retrieved. Users can use this ID at GAS. When a folder is opened, all files in the folder are cached.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
