<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calendar on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/calendar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calendar on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 16:04:18 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/calendar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sample Scripts for Creating New Event with Google Meet Link to Google Calendar using Various Languages</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 16:04:18 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages. When I saw the official document of &amp;ldquo;Add video and phone conferences to events&amp;rdquo;, in the current stage, I can see only the sample script for Javascript. But I saw the several questions related to this for various languages. So I published the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing A Lot Of Google Calendar Events using Batch Requests with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/12/managing-a-lot-of-google-calendar-events-using-batch-requests-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:14:27 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/12/managing-a-lot-of-google-calendar-events-using-batch-requests-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is the sample scripts for managing a lot of Google Calendar Events using the batch requests with Google Apps Script.
Description When we want to manage the events of Google Calendar, we have 2 ways. One is the use of Calendar service. Another is the use of Calendar API. In the case of them, when we want to manage a lot of calendar events, unfortunately, both ways have no batch requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Event ID from Event URL of Google Calendar using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/09/retrieving-event-id-from-event-url-of-google-calendar-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 14:13:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/09/retrieving-event-id-from-event-url-of-google-calendar-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for retrieving the event ID from the event URL of Google Calendar using Google Apps Script.
The event URL is like https://www.google.com/calendar/event?###. At the event URL, ### of https://www.google.com/calendar/event?### is not the event ID. So it is required to convert it.
Sample script var eventUrl = &amp;#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/event?###&amp;#34;; var eventId = Utilities.newBlob(Utilities.base64Decode(eventUrl.split(&amp;#34;=&amp;#34;)[1]))  .getDataAsString()  .split(&amp;#34; &amp;#34;)[0]; Logger.log(eventId); </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Google Apps Script by Event Notification from Google Calendar</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/09/running-google-apps-script-by-event-notification-from-google-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 11:19:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/09/running-google-apps-script-by-event-notification-from-google-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Overview This is a simple method running Google Apps Script by the event notification from Google Calendar.
Description There are several event triggers in Google Apps Script. Ref1, Ref2 There is an event trigger for Google Calendar. The official document says An installable calendar event trigger runs when a user&#39;s calendar events are updated—created, edited, or deleted.. Ref3 If I want to use the trigger when the event in the calendar is starts and finished, it is required to use Calendar API by preparing the URL for receiving from Google.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
