<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XLSX on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/xlsx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in XLSX on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 14:31:50 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/xlsx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importing Microsoft Excel to Google Spreadsheet using Custom Function with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/03/13/importing-microsoft-excel-to-google-spreadsheet-using-custom-function-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 14:31:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/03/13/importing-microsoft-excel-to-google-spreadsheet-using-custom-function-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for importing Microsoft Excel (XLSX) data to Google Spreadsheet using a custom function with Google Apps Script.
Usage 1. Install SheetJS library. Please copy the script of the SheetJS library from https://cdn.sheetjs.com/xlsx-latest/package/dist/xlsx.full.min.js, and paste the script to the script editor of Google Spreadsheet, and save the script.
In this case, I would like to recommend the following flow.
 Add a new script to the script editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directly Retrieving Values from XLSX data using SheetJS with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/03/12/directly-retrieving-values-from-xlsx-data-using-sheetjs-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 12:41:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/03/12/directly-retrieving-values-from-xlsx-data-using-sheetjs-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Updated on July 8, 2023
In the current stage, unfortunately, the built-in methods of Google Apps Script cannot directly retrieve the values from the XLSX data. From this situation, I have created DocsServiceApp. When this Google Apps Script library is used, the values are directly retrieved from XLSX data by parsing XML data of XLSX data.
Here, as another approach, I would like to introduce a sample script for directly retrieving the values from XLSX data using SheetJS with Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
