<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Report on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Report on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:21:54 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark: Effect of Comprehension for GAS</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/07/benchmark-effect-of-comprehension-for-gas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 09:21:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/07/benchmark-effect-of-comprehension-for-gas/</guid>
      <description>Description There are a limit executing time for Google Apps Script (GAS). It&amp;rsquo;s 6 minutes. So users have to pay attention to the process cost of the script. GAS can use JavaScript 1.7. This means to be able to be used comprehension for GAS.
In this report, the process cost for the comprehension has been investigated. The normal for loop was used as the competitor. As a result, it was found that the comprehension can be used one of methods for reducing the process cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Library - souwapy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library---souwapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 13:38:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library---souwapy/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;ldquo;souwapy&amp;rdquo; is a library for summing array elements with high speed by new algorithm (Pyramid method). The speed is faster than csv and panbdas module of python and v8 engine of node.js. The souwapy module is 2.3 and 3.1 times faster than csv and pandas module, respectively. This was really surprised me. It was found that the theory was correct.
At first, I have created this theory for Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - SOUWA_GAS - Effects on Optimized Codes of Pyramid Method</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library---souwa_gas---effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library---souwa_gas---effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</guid>
      <description>Kanshi TANAIKE 
Abstract I have already reported that the pyramid method is one of very effectively algolithms for summing string elements in an array using Google Apps Script (GAS). This report describes the adaptability of the pyramid method to any languages except for GAS. c++ (g++), Go, Java, Javascript on Node.js, Python and Ruby were chosen as the sample languages. In those languages, there are languages which have the distinctive commands for summing the array elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Algorithms for Summation of Array Elements</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/improved-algorithms-for-summation-of-array-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 14:39:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/improved-algorithms-for-summation-of-array-elements/</guid>
      <description>Kanshi TANAIKE 
Abstract I considered an efficient algorithm for summation of array elements. All elements in an array are string. When those elements are summed using scripts, a standard method is to add each element in order. If the script is run without any optimize, the process becomes gradually sluggish, because the total amount of active data during the summation process is proportional to the square of the number of array elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>