<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2A on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2A on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:37:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Tool Space Interference: Bridging Google ADK and A2A SDK via Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/01/overcoming-tool-space-interference-bridging-google-adk-and-a2a-sdk-via-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:37:00 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/01/overcoming-tool-space-interference-bridging-google-adk-and-a2a-sdk-via-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/37e4c20b090ad607d87f359b7ae72092&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20260101a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article introduces a Google Apps Script-based Agent2Agent architecture to solve Tool Space Interference. While the provided demonstration utilizes a single server for testing purposes, the architecture is designed for distributed task execution. By running multiple category-specific A2A servers in parallel, users can achieve scalable, high-efficiency agent networks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the Model Context Protocol (MCP) standardizes LLM connectivity, the Agent2Agent (A2A) paradigm is becoming essential for executing complex, multi-step tasks. However, integrating a high volume of tools often triggers &amp;ldquo;Tool Space Interference (TSI)&amp;quot;—a phenomenon where verbose metadata saturates context windows and degrades reasoning accuracy. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/nexus-mcp-a-unified-gateway-for-scalable-and-deterministic-mcp-server-aggregation-3211f0adc603&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/blog/tool-space-interference-in-the-mcp-era-designing-for-agent-compatibility-at-scale/&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; Current industry guidelines suggest a &amp;ldquo;soft limit&amp;rdquo; of 20 functions per agent; exceeding this threshold frequently results in hallucinations and logic failures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consolidating Generative AI Protocols: A Single Server Solution for MCP and A2A</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:18:25 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/f6e92df66a3a4f057f9bcae7c9d8a339&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20250619a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A new unified Google Apps Script now deploys both Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) networks as a single server, streamlining AI model integration for Google Workspace users.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rapid growth of generative AI has led to increasing integration between AI models, exemplified by protocols like the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) Protocol. Recently, I released MCPApp and A2AApp, which establish the MCP and A2A networks using Google Apps Script. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/gmail-processing-using-mcp-network-powered-by-google-apps-script-5ede2a25c94e&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/enabling-collaborative-agent-systems-through-google-apps-script-based-agent2agent-a2a-network-19e3d0472eaa&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; This approach offers significant advantages for users of Google Workspace and Google APIs, as it enables seamless authorization and integration of these resources directly within the applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - A2AApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-a2aapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 11:07:35 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-a2aapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;a2aapp-was-updated-to-v201&#34;&gt;A2AApp was updated to v2.0.1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;v2.0.1 (May 29, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From v2.0.1, A2AApp can also be used as a library. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanaikech/A2AApp/tree/master/Use_A2AApp_as_library&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can see the detail information here &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanaikech/A2AApp&#34;&gt;https://github.com/tanaikech/A2AApp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Collaborative Agent Systems through Google Apps Script-based Agent2Agent (A2A) Network</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/28/enabling-collaborative-agent-systems-through-google-apps-script-based-agent2agent-a2a-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:49:31 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/28/enabling-collaborative-agent-systems-through-google-apps-script-based-agent2agent-a2a-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/0dcee0009d8037262b60c8723283e9a5&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20250528a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This report details the Agent2Agent (A2A) network built with Google Apps Script&amp;rsquo;s Web Apps. It facilitates communication between diverse AI agents, overcoming platform limitations. Key improvements include parallel task execution with asynchronous processes and enhanced security through secure access token handling and user-specific Web App availability, demonstrating a robust and secure A2A implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This report details an updated implementation of &lt;strong&gt;Agent2Agent (A2A)&lt;/strong&gt;, an open protocol designed to enable communication and collaboration between diverse AI agents. The goal of A2A is to overcome limitations of isolated platforms, allowing AI agents to work together on complex tasks while maintaining their internal structures. I recently published a report titled &amp;ldquo;Building Agent2Agent (A2A) Server with Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/building-agent2agent-a2a-server-with-google-apps-script-d3efd32c7ca7&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; This updated report focuses on successfully creating an &lt;strong&gt;A2A network&lt;/strong&gt; using &lt;strong&gt;Google Apps Script&amp;rsquo;s Web Apps functionality&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Agent2Agent (A2A) Server with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/16/building-agent2agent-a2a-server-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:16:05 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/16/building-agent2agent-a2a-server-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/85c4762a8b8c6c7d8bee1d7ed32ade34&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20250516a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exploring Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol implementation in Google Apps Script seamlessly allows AI agents to access Google Workspace data and functions. This could enable complex workflows and automation, overcoming platform silos for integrated AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agent2Agent (A2A) is a proposed open protocol facilitating communication and collaboration among diverse AI agents, aiming to overcome platform silos and enable complex tasks while preserving agent opacity. This report examines the feasibility of implementing a core A2A server component using Google Apps Script within Google Workspace. Such an implementation could seamlessly allow AI agents to securely access and utilize data and functionalities across Google services like Docs, Sheets, and Gmail via a standardized protocol. This would enable sophisticated AI-powered workflows and automation directly linked to user data. A sample script demonstrates the technical potential despite the current lack of a dedicated Apps Script SDK for A2A. While acknowledging potential Apps Script limitations, such as execution time, this exploratory approach remains valuable for developing internal or user-centric AI applications and integrations within Google Workspace. A successful demonstration could potentially highlight the capabilities of Google Apps Script.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
