<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2A on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2A on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:37:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Tool Space Interference: Bridging Google ADK and A2A SDK via Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/01/overcoming-tool-space-interference-bridging-google-adk-and-a2a-sdk-via-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 16:37:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/01/overcoming-tool-space-interference-bridging-google-adk-and-a2a-sdk-via-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a Google Apps Script-based Agent2Agent architecture to solve Tool Space Interference. While the provided demonstration utilizes a single server for testing purposes, the architecture is designed for distributed task execution. By running multiple category-specific A2A servers in parallel, users can achieve scalable, high-efficiency agent networks.
Introduction As the Model Context Protocol (MCP) standardizes LLM connectivity, the Agent2Agent (A2A) paradigm is becoming essential for executing complex, multi-step tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consolidating Generative AI Protocols: A Single Server Solution for MCP and A2A</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:18:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract A new unified Google Apps Script now deploys both Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) networks as a single server, streamlining AI model integration for Google Workspace users.
Introduction The rapid growth of generative AI has led to increasing integration between AI models, exemplified by protocols like the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) Protocol. Recently, I released MCPApp and A2AApp, which establish the MCP and A2A networks using Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - A2AApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-a2aapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 11:07:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-a2aapp/</guid>
      <description>A2AApp was updated to v2.0.1   v2.0.1 (May 29, 2025)
 From v2.0.1, A2AApp can also be used as a library. Ref    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/A2AApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Collaborative Agent Systems through Google Apps Script-based Agent2Agent (A2A) Network</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/28/enabling-collaborative-agent-systems-through-google-apps-script-based-agent2agent-a2a-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:49:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/28/enabling-collaborative-agent-systems-through-google-apps-script-based-agent2agent-a2a-network/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report details the Agent2Agent (A2A) network built with Google Apps Script&amp;rsquo;s Web Apps. It facilitates communication between diverse AI agents, overcoming platform limitations. Key improvements include parallel task execution with asynchronous processes and enhanced security through secure access token handling and user-specific Web App availability, demonstrating a robust and secure A2A implementation.
Introduction This report details an updated implementation of Agent2Agent (A2A), an open protocol designed to enable communication and collaboration between diverse AI agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Agent2Agent (A2A) Server with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/16/building-agent2agent-a2a-server-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:16:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/16/building-agent2agent-a2a-server-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Exploring Agent2Agent (A2A) protocol implementation in Google Apps Script seamlessly allows AI agents to access Google Workspace data and functions. This could enable complex workflows and automation, overcoming platform silos for integrated AI applications.
Introduction Agent2Agent (A2A) is a proposed open protocol facilitating communication and collaboration among diverse AI agents, aiming to overcome platform silos and enable complex tasks while preserving agent opacity. This report examines the feasibility of implementing a core A2A server component using Google Apps Script within Google Workspace.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
