<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gist on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/gist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gist on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:27:22 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/gist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - GistChecker</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/gas-library---gistchecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:27:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/gas-library---gistchecker/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a GAS library for notifying the change of number of comments, stars and forks of own Gists as an email using Google Apps Script.
Description Recently, I noticed that when a comment was posted to own Gists, and the numbers of stars and forks of own Gists were changed, the notification mail is not sent. Also I knew that in the current stage, there are no official methods for notifying them, yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - gislack</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/30/updated-cli-tool---gislack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:40:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/30/updated-cli-tool---gislack/</guid>
      <description>gislack is a CLI tool to submit files to both Gist and Slack.
 v1.0.1 (June 30, 2017)  Some modifications related to error handling.   Please check it out. https://github.com/tanaikech/gislack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text Plugin - gislacks</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/sublime-text-plugin---gislacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 13:33:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/sublime-text-plugin---gislacks/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a plugin of Sublime Text 3 for submitting files to both Gist and Slack.
Description I like to use Sublime Text for developing scripts. And when I discuss about developing scripts, I often use Slack. When I submitted a script to Slack, I had saved the script to Gist as a backup. I had done manually this on my browser. Namely, I wanted to be saving the revision of script while I&amp;rsquo;m discussing about the script at Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - gislack</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/cli-tool---gislack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 12:59:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/cli-tool---gislack/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to submit files to both Gist and Slack.
Description When I discuss about developing scripts, I often use Slack. When I submitted a script to Slack, I had saved the script to Gist as a backup. I had done manually this on my browser. Namely, I wanted to be saving the revision of script while I&amp;rsquo;m discussing about the script at Slack. Recently, I wished this process had been able to be automatically run.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>