<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Model Context Protocol on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/model-context-protocol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Model Context Protocol on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:24:07 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/model-context-protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nexus-MCP: A Unified Gateway for Scalable and Deterministic MCP Server Aggregation</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/25/nexus-mcp-a-unified-gateway-for-scalable-and-deterministic-mcp-server-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:24:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/25/nexus-mcp-a-unified-gateway-for-scalable-and-deterministic-mcp-server-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Nexus-MCP resolves &amp;ldquo;Tool Space Interference&amp;rdquo; in Large Language Models by aggregating multiple MCP servers into a single gateway. Utilizing a strictly deterministic 4-phase workflow—Discovery, Mapping, Schema Verification, and Bridged Execution—it prevents context saturation and tool hallucinations, enabling the use of massive tool ecosystems without sacrificing reasoning accuracy.
Introduction The integration of Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity with the Model Context Protocol (MCP) has significantly expanded the capabilities of LLM-based agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modularizing AI Agents: Integrating Google Apps Script Libraries with Gemini CLI and Antigravity</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/11/modularizing-ai-agents-integrating-google-apps-script-libraries-with-gemini-cli-and-antigravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:39:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/11/modularizing-ai-agents-integrating-google-apps-script-libraries-with-gemini-cli-and-antigravity/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a major update to gas-fakes enabling dynamic loading of Google Apps Script libraries. This enhancement allows developers to build modular, maintainable Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers. We demonstrate this by integrating sophisticated library-based tools with Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity for seamless Google Workspace automation.
Introduction I recently published an article titled &amp;ldquo;Power of Google Apps Script: Building MCP Server Tools for Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity in Google Workspace Automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of Google Apps Script: Building MCP Server Tools for Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity in Google Workspace Automation</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/03/power-of-google-apps-script-building-mcp-server-tools-for-gemini-cli-and-google-antigravity-in-google-workspace-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:37:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/03/power-of-google-apps-script-building-mcp-server-tools-for-gemini-cli-and-google-antigravity-in-google-workspace-automation/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to build Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools directly using Google Apps Script. By leveraging the gas-fakes CLI, developers can execute Google Apps Script locally to automate Google Workspace via Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity, streamlining development and eliminating the overhead of dynamic tool creation.
Introduction With the rapid advancement of generative AI, ensuring the security of executing AI-generated scripts is of paramount importance to prevent arbitrary code execution vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Era for Google Apps Script: Unlocking the Future of Google Workspace Automation with Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/01/a-new-era-for-google-apps-script-unlocking-the-future-of-google-workspace-automation-with-natural-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:19:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/01/a-new-era-for-google-apps-script-unlocking-the-future-of-google-workspace-automation-with-natural-language/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article redefines Google Apps Script (GAS) as a central integration hub in the AI era. It introduces the forefront of Google Workspace automation, realized through the fusion of the Model Context Protocol (MCP), Agent2Agent (A2A), and the Gemini CLI ecosystem. I cover everything from data integration bridging local and cloud environments (RAG) and sandbox technologies for safely executing AI-generated GAS, to the coordination of autonomous agents on the newly released Google Antigravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Google Antigravity: Unlocking the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:08:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to integrate the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI with Google Antigravity. It addresses a Model Context Protocol (MCP) tool naming incompatibility using a custom proxy script, enabling seamless, authenticated automation of Google Workspace tasks directly within the Antigravity IDE environment.
Introduction Since its release, the Gemini CLI has been rapidly adopted across various development scenarios. Ref Its utility increased significantly with the introduction of Gemini CLI Extensions, which simplify the installation and management of Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Automation in Google Workspace: Bridging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:43:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article explores automating Google Workspace by integrating Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers. We demonstrate how to overcome tool limits and utilize custom extensions to enable AI agents to securely execute scripts, manage files, and perform RAG-based tasks using private data.
Introduction Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 are ushering in a new era of &amp;ldquo;Agent-First&amp;rdquo; development, transforming how we interact with cloud environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Generation Google Apps Script Development: Leveraging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:20:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates a cutting-edge workflow for Google Apps Script development using Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0. By integrating gas-fakes via the Model Context Protocol (MCP), we establish an environment where autonomous agents can generate, unit-test, and execute cloud-based scripts locally, revolutionizing the standard GAS development lifecycle.
Introduction Google Antigravity has officially been released. Ref This is a revolutionary &amp;ldquo;Agent-first&amp;rdquo; IDE powered by Gemini 3, designed to empower autonomous AI agents to plan, code, and verify tasks across the Editor, Terminal, and Browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Data Silos to Unified RAG: Gemini CLI Extensions Unify Local and Google Workspace for a Powerful File Search</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/15/from-data-silos-to-unified-rag-gemini-cli-extensions-unify-local-and-google-workspace-for-a-powerful-file-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:01:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/15/from-data-silos-to-unified-rag-gemini-cli-extensions-unify-local-and-google-workspace-for-a-powerful-file-search/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to create a unified file search for Gemini, integrating disconnected local files and Google Workspace data. Using a Google Apps Script-powered extension, users can directly ingest data from Drive, Sheets, and Gmail, enabling a powerful, context-aware RAG system.
Introduction 1. The Challenge of Data Silos In modern enterprises, data is fragmented. It lives on local machines, in Google Drive, within Google Sheets, and across countless emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI Extension: FileSearchStore-extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/gemini-cli-extension-filesearchstore-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:38:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/gemini-cli-extension-filesearchstore-extension/</guid>
      <description>Here introduces a new Gemini CLI extension that integrates File Search feature. This tool establishes a fully managed Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system directly on the command line.
The extension is designed to simplify the use of the Gemini API&amp;rsquo;s File Search, a powerful new feature that enables RAG grounded in personal or proprietary knowledge bases. While the underlying API requires scripting, this Node.js-built CLI extension allows users to seamlessly manage File Search stores and generate context-aware content grounded in their private documents without having to leave the terminal interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating File Search with the Gemini CLI Extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/integrating-file-search-with-the-gemini-cli-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:27:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/integrating-file-search-with-the-gemini-cli-extension/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a Gemini CLI extension that integrates File Search feature. This tool provides a fully managed Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system directly in your command line, enabling content generation grounded in your private documents and data.
Introduction The Gemini API recently introduced File Search, a powerful feature that enables Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) using your own documents as a knowledge base. This allows you to generate content grounded in personal or proprietary information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Google Apps Script Development</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/29/next-level-google-apps-script-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:41:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/29/next-level-google-apps-script-development/</guid>
      <description>GitHub
Abstract This article introduces a powerful method for developing and testing Google Apps Script (GAS) locally. By leveraging the gas-fakes library, you can build a secure, local Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, enabling the creation of AI-powered tools for Google Workspace automation without deploying to the cloud.
Introduction gas-fakes, developed by Bruce McPherson, is an innovative library that enables Google Apps Script (GAS) code to run directly in a local environment by substituting GAS classes and methods with their corresponding Google APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure and Streamlined Google Apps Script Development with gas-fakes CLI and Gemini CLI Extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/27/secure-and-streamlined-google-apps-script-development-with-gas-fakes-cli-and-gemini-cli-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 14:57:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/27/secure-and-streamlined-google-apps-script-development-with-gas-fakes-cli-and-gemini-cli-extension/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This document introduces a powerful integration of the gas-fakes CLI and a Gemini CLI extension, creating a secure and streamlined development workflow for Google Apps Script. This setup enables local testing of AI-generated scripts in a secure sandbox, preventing unintended access to your Google Drive, and provides a seamless transition to cloud deployment.
Introduction The gas-fakes project by Bruce McPherson is a groundbreaking endeavor that recreates the Google Apps Script (GAS) execution environment on Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI Extension for GAS Development Kit</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/26/gemini-cli-extension-for-gas-development-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:18:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/26/gemini-cli-extension-for-gas-development-kit/</guid>
      <description>I created a Gemini CLI extension as a GAS Development Kit. For this, I developed the CLI of gas-fakes.
Repository https://github.com/tanaikech/gas-development-kit-extension
Installation 1. Install Gemini CLI First, install the Gemini CLI using npm:
npm install -g @google/gemini-cli Next, you will need to authorize the CLI. Follow the instructions provided in the official documentation.
2. Install Clasp Even when Clasp is not installed, when gas-fakes is installed, you can run Google Apps Script in a sandbox using gas-fakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Google Apps Script Development with Gemini CLI Extensions and VSCode</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/21/streamlining-google-apps-script-development-with-gemini-cli-extensions-and-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:28:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/21/streamlining-google-apps-script-development-with-gemini-cli-extensions-and-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This guide explores a powerful, next-level workflow for Google Apps Script (GAS) development by integrating Gemini CLI Extensions with Visual Studio Code (VSCode). This combination streamlines the entire development process, from script creation and local testing in a secure sandbox to deploying and managing projects, all within a unified and efficient environment.
Introduction Visual Studio Code (VSCode) is widely recognized as a premier source code editor. The release of the Gemini CLI has dramatically transformed script development by bringing advanced AI capabilities directly into the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Developer&#39;s Guide to Building Gemini CLI Extensions</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/16/a-developers-guide-to-building-gemini-cli-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 13:14:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/16/a-developers-guide-to-building-gemini-cli-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This guide offers a comprehensive walkthrough of the essential steps and key considerations for developing Gemini CLI extensions. It covers setting up a sample project, configuring the gemini-extension.json file, local testing, and automating dependency management with GitHub Actions, providing developers with the foundational knowledge to create their own custom tools.
Introduction After the release of Gemini CLI Extensions, a growing community of users is developing a wide range of extensions to enhance their command-line workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI Extension: ToolsForMCPServer-extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/15/gemini-cli-extension-toolsformcpserver-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:26:26 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/15/gemini-cli-extension-toolsformcpserver-extension/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer-extension This Gemini CLI Extension simplifies Google Workspace automation. It installs a local Model Context Protocol (MCP) server that communicates with a powerful, securely authorized backend built on Google Apps Script Web Apps, overcoming previous complex setup and performance bottlenecks.
You can see the details at my repository.
https://github.com/tanaikech/ToolsForMCPServer-extension</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified Google Workspace Automation with Gemini CLI Extensions</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/15/simplified-google-workspace-automation-with-gemini-cli-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:06:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/15/simplified-google-workspace-automation-with-gemini-cli-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This project simplifies Google Workspace automation by using a Gemini CLI Extension. It installs a local Model Context Protocol (MCP) server that communicates with a powerful, securely authorized backend built on Google Apps Script Web Apps, overcoming previous complex setup and performance bottlenecks.
Introduction In order to achieve Google Workspace Automation with seamless authorization and safety, I have published a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server built by Google Apps Script Web Apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Tool Creation for Google Workspace Automation with Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/09/dynamic-tool-creation-for-google-workspace-automation-with-gemini-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:43:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/09/dynamic-tool-creation-for-google-workspace-automation-with-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article presents a method for optimizing Google Workspace automation by dynamically converting frequently used, AI-generated Google Apps Scripts into permanent, reusable tools. By integrating the Gemini CLI with a gas-fakes sandbox via an MCP server, we demonstrate how to securely add and manage these custom tools, reducing operational costs and improving efficiency.
Introduction When using generative AI to create scripts, ensuring the secure execution of the generated code is critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collaborative Dialogue Between Gemini CLI and Copilot CLI Through MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/02/a-collaborative-dialogue-between-gemini-cli-and-copilot-cli-through-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 14:59:18 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/10/02/a-collaborative-dialogue-between-gemini-cli-and-copilot-cli-through-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a method for integrating Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini CLI and GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Copilot CLI using the Model Context Protocol (MCP). By configuring one CLI as an MCP server, the other can invoke it from a prompt, enabling a powerful, collaborative interaction between the two AI assistants for enhanced development workflows.
Introduction Recently, GitHub released the Copilot CLI, a command-line interface that brings the power of GitHub Copilot directly to your terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure and Conversational Google Workspace Automation: Integrating Gemini CLI with a gas-fakes MCP Server</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/30/secure-and-conversational-google-workspace-automation-integrating-gemini-cli-with-a-gas-fakes-mcp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 16:15:11 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/30/secure-and-conversational-google-workspace-automation-integrating-gemini-cli-with-a-gas-fakes-mcp-server/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a method for securely executing AI-generated Google Apps Script. By implementing a &amp;ldquo;fake-sandbox&amp;rdquo; using the gas-fakes library as an MCP server, users can empower the Gemini CLI to safely automate Google Workspace tasks with granular, file-specific permissions, avoiding significant security risks.
Introduction &amp;ldquo;Have you ever faced a task that isn&amp;rsquo;t part of your routine but is tedious to do manually, like, &amp;lsquo;I need to add a &amp;ldquo;[For Review]&amp;rdquo; prefix to the titles of all Google Docs in a specific folder this afternoon&amp;rsquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Content Creation: A Guide to Using Gemini CLI, MCP Server, and VSCode</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/24/streamlining-content-creation-a-guide-to-using-gemini-cli-mcp-server-and-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 15:14:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/24/streamlining-content-creation-a-guide-to-using-gemini-cli-mcp-server-and-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This guide explores a powerful workflow for generating articles and other content by integrating Gemini CLI, a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, and Visual Studio Code (VSCode). Discover how to leverage this combination for efficient, context-aware content creation, modification, and distribution, complete with practical examples and prompts.
Introduction The integration of Gemini CLI with Visual Studio Code (VSCode) creates a highly efficient and context-aware environment for developers and writers alike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Gemini CLI: A Node.js Wrapper for Google Apps Script MCP Servers</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/17/accelerating-gemini-cli-a-node.js-wrapper-for-google-apps-script-mcp-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 16:09:33 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/17/accelerating-gemini-cli-a-node.js-wrapper-for-google-apps-script-mcp-servers/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a Node.js wrapper that dramatically reduces the startup time for the Gemini CLI when used with MCP servers built on Google Apps Script. This optimization enhances user experience by accelerating the initialization process, achieving a speed boost of approximately 15 times.
1. Introduction The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is a vital open standard enabling AI agents to connect with external tools and data sources for complex, real-world tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/15/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:09:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/15/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.29   v1.0.29 (September 15, 2025)
  The following 5 tools were added. These tools provide the information for building the request body of Google APIs.
 explanation_analytics_data_properties_runReport explanation_analytics_data_properties_runRealtimeReport explanation_manage_google_sheets_using_sheets_api explanation_manage_google_docs_using_docs_api explanation_manage_google_slides_using_slides_api    The following 8 tools were updated.
 get_google_sheet_object_using_sheets_api manage_google_sheets_using_sheets_api get_google_doc_object_using_docs_api manage_google_docs_using_docs_api get_google_slides_object_using_slides_api manage_google_slides_using_slides_api analytics_data_properties_runReport analytics_data_properties_runRealtimeReport      You can see the detailed information here https://github.com/tanaikech/ToolsForMCPServer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:36:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.28   v1.0.28 (September 11, 2025)
  The following 9 tools were added.
 create_document_body_in_google_docs remove_files_on_google_drive maps_get_route maps_convert_location_to_lat_lon maps_convert_lat_lon_to_location maps_create_map explanation_create_maps_url explanation_reference_generate_google_apps_script explanation_reference_export_google_sheets_as_pdf    A bug of a tool &amp;ldquo;convert_mimetype_of_file_on_google_drive&amp;rdquo; was removed. This is from this issue report.
    You can see the detailed information here https://github.com/tanaikech/ToolsForMCPServer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps with Natural Language: Integrated Collaboration through Gemini CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/google-maps-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:16:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/google-maps-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists Abstract This article demonstrates integrating Google Maps with natural language using the Gemini CLI and an MCP server. This powerful combination allows users to automate complex location-based tasks, such as route planning and information retrieval, through simple, intuitive text-based prompts. Introduction The Gemini CLI, when paired with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers, is a powerful tool for integrating various applications with natural language. When the MCP servers are built</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/22/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:33:11 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/22/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.27   v1.0.27 (August 22, 2025)
  Following 6 tools for Google Analytics were added.
 analytics_admin_accountSummaries_list: Retrieves a list of all Google Analytics accounts accessible by the current user analytics_admin_properties_get: Get detailed information about a single Google Analytics property analytics_data_properties_runReport: Fetches a custom report from a Google Analytics property analytics_data_properties_runRealtimeReport: Generates a customized report of real-time event data from a Google Analytics property      You can see the detailed information here https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Web Page Insights with Natural Language using Gemini CLI, Google Analytics, and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/22/streamlining-web-page-insights-with-natural-language-using-gemini-cli-google-analytics-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:24:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/22/streamlining-web-page-insights-with-natural-language-using-gemini-cli-google-analytics-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report introduces a powerful method for automating Google Analytics tasks using the Gemini CLI and a custom MCP (Model Context Protocol) server built with Google Apps Script. This integration enables streamlined web page analysis through simple natural language commands, simplifying authorization and complex data retrieval workflows.
Introduction Accessing and interpreting web analytics data often involves navigating complex interfaces and manual report generation. However, the emergence of natural language interfaces is changing this paradigm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unifying Google Workspace with Natural Language: Integrated Collaboration through Gemini CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/18/unifying-google-workspace-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 16:12:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/18/unifying-google-workspace-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This document demonstrates a transformative method for unifying Google Workspace applications by using natural language. Through the integration of the Gemini CLI with MCP, this approach empowers users to intuitively manage Google Drive, Gmail, Google Calendar, Drive Activity, and Google People. Complex tasks and collaborative workflows are streamlined into simple, conversational text commands.
Introduction In today&amp;rsquo;s dynamic, collaborative environments, managing document workflows, tracking changes, and coordinating team efforts can be fragmented and inefficient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Classroom Automation: Gemini CLI, Google Classroom, and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/10/next-level-classroom-automation-gemini-cli-google-classroom-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 14:20:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/10/next-level-classroom-automation-gemini-cli-google-classroom-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Automate Google Classroom management with natural language. This guide details using the Gemini CLI and an MCP server to streamline creating classes, managing assignments, and interacting with students.
Introduction Unlock the power of natural language to command your Google Workspace. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently demonstrated how you can automate Google Workspace applications using simple, conversational commands through the Gemini CLI and the MCP (Model Context Protocol) server.
My previous reports detailed how to harness natural language for automating tasks in Google Sheets and Google Calendar:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - MCPApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/06/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 10:38:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/06/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</guid>
      <description>MCPApp was updated to v2.0.7   v2.0.7 (August 6, 2025)
  Starting with v2.0.7, you can now selectively enable or disable the LockService.
 By default, this library runs with the LockService enabled. To disable it, simply modify return new MCPApp.mcpApp({ accessKey: &amp;quot;sample&amp;quot; }) to return new MCPApp.mcpApp({ accessKey: &amp;quot;sample&amp;quot;, lock: false }). When the LockService is disabled (lock: false), asynchronous requests from clients like the Gemini CLI may see an increase in processing speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:37:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.13   v1.0.13 (August 1, 2025)
 prompts/get was updated. And, 3 prompts were added.    You can see the detailed information here https://github.com/tanaikech/ToolsForMCPServer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - MCPApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:35:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</guid>
      <description>MCPApp was updated to v2.0.6   v2.0.6 (August 1, 2025)
 &amp;ldquo;prompts/get&amp;rdquo; method was updated.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/MCPApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Guide to Using Prompts in Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/enhanced-guide-to-using-prompts-in-gemini-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 16:08:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/08/01/enhanced-guide-to-using-prompts-in-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report provides a comprehensive overview of how to utilize prompts within the Gemini Command-Line Interface (CLI). Leveraging a Google Apps Script MCP server, we will explore practical examples, including roadmap generation, real-time weather inquiries, and Google Drive file searches. This enhanced document offers more in-depth explanations and a broader context to empower users in their understanding and application of these powerful features.
Introduction The Model Context Protocol (MCP) establishes a standardized framework for servers to offer clients predefined, structured prompt templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/31/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:20:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/31/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.12   v1.0.12 (July 31, 2025)
 At Gemini CLI v0.1.15, prompts/list was called even when prompts wasn&amp;rsquo;t included in capabilities. This resulted in the error Error discovering prompts from gas_web_apps: MCP error -32001: Request timed out when prompts wasn&amp;rsquo;t returned for prompts/list. To resolve this, I updated ToolsForMCPServer to return an empty array for prompts, which eliminated the error. Consequently, with this update in v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - MCPApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/31/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 10:17:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/31/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</guid>
      <description>MCPApp was updated to v2.0.5   v2.0.5 (July 31, 2025)
 A bug was removed.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/MCPApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Data Automation: Gemini CLI, Google Calendar, and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/29/next-level-data-automation-gemini-cli-google-calendar-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 13:33:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/29/next-level-data-automation-gemini-cli-google-calendar-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report demonstrates managing Google Calendar from the command line using Gemini CLI and an MCP server, enabling powerful, scriptable automation for your schedule.
Introduction Following up on my previous report, &amp;ldquo;Next-Level Data Automation: Gemini CLI, Google Sheets, and MCP,&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m excited to present the next installment in this series. My earlier report, published on Medium, detailed an innovative approach to managing Google Sheets through the powerful combination of Gemini CLI and an MCP server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/26/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 15:04:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/26/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.10   v1.0.10 (July 26, 2025)
 When I updated Gemini CLI from v0.1.12 to v0.1.13, an issue related to the schema of MCP occurred. Ref So, as a workaround at the time, I updated this library. But when I updated Gemini CLI to v0.1.14, I confirmed that the previous schema could be used. So, I reimplemented the previous schema. By this, the request body for APIs can be directly generated using Gemini CLI v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/24/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 13:43:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/24/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.9   v1.0.9 (July 24, 2025)
 The following 2 new tools were added.   description_youtube: Describe a YouTube video by providing the URL. create_google_docs_from_markdown_on_google_drive: Create a Google Document from a markdown format.    You can see the detailed information here https://github.com/tanaikech/ToolsForMCPServer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/23/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 13:11:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/23/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.8   v1.0.8 (July 23, 2025)
 An issue occurred when I updated Gemini CLI from v0.1.12 to v0.1.13. Ref Fortunately, Google is already aware of this issue, and I&amp;rsquo;m awaiting a resolution. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ve received emails about it, so I&amp;rsquo;ve updated ToolsForMCPServer for Gemini CLI v0.1.13. The detailed updates are as follows: I confirmed that all tools in ToolsForMCPServer v1.0.8 worked when tested with Gemini CLI v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/19/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 16:17:26 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/19/updated-gas-library-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>ToolsForMCPServer was updated to v1.0.7   v1.0.7 (July 19, 2025)
 Added a getToolList method for retrieving all current tools in the library. Tools can be filtered using enables or disables as an array argument for the getTools method. If enables is used, only the tools specified in the enables array will be used. If disables is used, all tools except those specified in the disables array will be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Google Docs, Sheets, and Slides by Natural Language with Gemini CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/17/managing-google-docs-sheets-and-slides-by-natural-language-with-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 15:48:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/17/managing-google-docs-sheets-and-slides-by-natural-language-with-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report explores an optimized approach to integrating the Gemini CLI with Google Workspace via an MCP server. Traditionally, this process requires numerous custom tools, which increases development costs. We propose leveraging the inherent JSON schema requirements of the MCP server tools to directly construct request bodies for the batchUpdate methods of the Google Docs, Sheets, and Slides APIs. This approach aims to consolidate document management into just three core tools, significantly streamlining development and offering a scalable, cost-effective solution for Google Workspace automation and broader API integrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Level Data Automation: Gemini CLI, Google Sheets, and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/12/next-level-data-automation-gemini-cli-google-sheets-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 11:24:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/12/next-level-data-automation-gemini-cli-google-sheets-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article explores the integration of the Gemini Command-Line Interface (CLI) with Google Sheets using the Model Context Protocol (MCP). It demonstrates how to leverage the open-source projects MCPApp and ToolsForMCPServer to create a bridge between the Gemini CLI and Google Workspace. This enables users to perform powerful data automation tasks, such as creating, reading, and modifying tables in Google Sheets directly from the command line, using natural language prompts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI: Featuring an Enhanced ToolsForMCPServer</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/09/gemini-cli-featuring-an-enhanced-toolsformcpserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 15:22:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/09/gemini-cli-featuring-an-enhanced-toolsformcpserver/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report introduces ToolsForMCPServer, an enhanced Google Apps Script library that expands the capabilities of Gemini CLI. It showcases new tools that streamline complex workflows, with a special emphasis on facilitating seamless file content transfer and management between a user&amp;rsquo;s local environment and Google Drive.
Introduction This report details significant enhancements to ToolsForMCPServer, a powerful Google Apps Script library designed to work in tandem with Gemini CLI. By integrating this library with a Model Context Protocol (MCP) server, the capabilities of Gemini CLI are dramatically expanded, especially in its interaction with Google Workspace services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing File Content Using Gemini CLI with an MCP Server Built by Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/08/processing-file-content-using-gemini-cli-with-an-mcp-server-built-by-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 15:17:21 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/08/processing-file-content-using-gemini-cli-with-an-mcp-server-built-by-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report details two methods for processing files using the Gemini CLI and a Google Apps Script MCP server: direct Base64 encoding and indirect transfer via the Google Drive API using ggsrun. The direct method proved ineffective due to token limits. The recommended approach, leveraging ggsrun, allows for efficient, scalable file transfers by using file IDs instead of embedding content within the prompt, enabling advanced automation capabilities.
Introduction This report demonstrates how to efficiently process file content using the Gemini CLI integrated with an MCP (Magical Control Panel) server built on Google Apps Script Web Apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI with MCP Server: Expanding Possibilities with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/03/gemini-cli-with-mcp-server-expanding-possibilities-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 15:45:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/07/03/gemini-cli-with-mcp-server-expanding-possibilities-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract The Gemini CLI provides a powerful command-line interface for interacting with Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini models. By leveraging the Model Context Protocol (MCP), the CLI can be extended with custom tools. This report explores the integration of the Gemini CLI with an MCP server built using Google Apps Script Web Apps. We demonstrate how this combination simplifies authorization for Google Workspace APIs (Gmail, Drive, Calendar, etc.), allowing Gemini to execute complex, multi-step tasks directly within the Google ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI with MCP Server Built by Web Apps of Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/27/gemini-cli-with-mcp-server-built-by-web-apps-of-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 16:12:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/27/gemini-cli-with-mcp-server-built-by-web-apps-of-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract The Gemini CLI can be integrated with Google Workspace via Google Apps Script to securely access personal data, enabling powerful automations like email summaries and calendar management.
Introduction The recently released Gemini CLI is a powerful command-line interface for interacting with Google&amp;rsquo;s Gemini models and cloud resources. Ref While powerful on its own, its utility can be significantly enhanced by connecting it to a user&amp;rsquo;s personal Google resources, such as Google Sheets, Docs, Slides, Gmail, and Calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consolidating Generative AI Protocols: A Single Server Solution for MCP and A2A</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 11:18:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/19/consolidating-generative-ai-protocols-a-single-server-solution-for-mcp-and-a2a/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract A new unified Google Apps Script now deploys both Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) networks as a single server, streamlining AI model integration for Google Workspace users.
Introduction The rapid growth of generative AI has led to increasing integration between AI models, exemplified by protocols like the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) Protocol. Recently, I released MCPApp and A2AApp, which establish the MCP and A2A networks using Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - MCPApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/12/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 15:36:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/12/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</guid>
      <description>MCPApp was updated to v2.0.0   v2.0.0 (June 12, 2025)
 From v2.0.0, both the MCP client and the MCP server can be built by Google Apps Script.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/MCPApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail Processing using MCP Network Powered by Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/12/gmail-processing-using-mcp-network-powered-by-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 15:06:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/12/gmail-processing-using-mcp-network-powered-by-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report details an MCP network using Google Apps Script for both server and client, enabling automated, secure Gmail processing to boost efficiency.
Introduction Recently, I published a report titled &amp;ldquo;Building Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server with Google Apps Script,&amp;rdquo; which you can find here. In that initial report, I demonstrated the feasibility of creating an MCP server using Google Apps Script, with Claude Desktop serving as the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - MCPApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 14:20:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/29/updated-gas-library-mcpapp/</guid>
      <description>MCPApp was updated to v1.0.2   v1.0.2 (May 29, 2025)
 From v1.0.2, in order to use MCPApp as a library, LockService is given.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/MCPApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Transfer: MCP Server (Web Apps/Google Apps Script) to MCP Client (Gemini/Python)</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/10/image-transfer-mcp-server-web-apps/google-apps-script-to-mcp-client-gemini/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 14:06:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/10/image-transfer-mcp-server-web-apps/google-apps-script-to-mcp-client-gemini/python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report details transferring image data via Model Context Protocol (MCP) from Google Apps Script server to a Python/Gemini client, extending capabilities for multimodal applications beyond text.
Introduction Following up on my previous report, &amp;ldquo;Building Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server with Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo; (Ref), which detailed the transfer of text data between the MCP server and client, this new report focuses on extending the protocol to handle image data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/08/building-model-context-protocol-mcp-server-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 15:29:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/08/building-model-context-protocol-mcp-server-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This text introduces the Model Context Protocol (MCP) for standardizing AI interaction with external systems. It explores the potential of using Google Apps Script (GAS) to host an MCP server, leveraging GAS&amp;rsquo;s integration with Google Workspace for data access. A sample script demonstrates feasibility, highlighting the current absence of an official GAS SDK. The work aims to foster understanding and encourage SDK development.
Introduction Recently, the Model Context Protocol (MCP) has emerged as a standard protocol for connecting AI applications with third-party systems and data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
