<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>map on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/map/</link>
    <description>Recent content in map on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:16:17 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/map/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google Maps with Natural Language: Integrated Collaboration through Gemini CLI and MCP</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/google-maps-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:16:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/09/11/google-maps-with-natural-language-integrated-collaboration-through-gemini-cli-and-mcp/</guid>
      <description>Gists Abstract This article demonstrates integrating Google Maps with natural language using the Gemini CLI and an MCP server. This powerful combination allows users to automate complex location-based tasks, such as route planning and information retrieval, through simple, intuitive text-based prompts. Introduction The Gemini CLI, when paired with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers, is a powerful tool for integrating various applications with natural language. When the MCP servers are built</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Route and Embedding Map using Custom Function on Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/14/search-route-and-embedding-map-using-custom-function-on-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 17:35:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/14/search-route-and-embedding-map-using-custom-function-on-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>This sample script is for searching route between place A and B and embedding a map by custom function on Spreadsheet.
I think that this method is one of various ideas.
Problem When the map is embedded to a cell on spreadsheet as an image, the function =IMAGE() is suitable for this situation. However, Class Maps, setFormula() for importing =IMAGE() and DriveApp.createFile() for creating images from maps also cannot be used for custom functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embedding a Map to a Cell using Custom Function on Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/04/embedding-a-map-to-a-cell-using-custom-function-on-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 12:02:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/04/embedding-a-map-to-a-cell-using-custom-function-on-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>This sample script embeds a map to a cell using custom function on Spreadsheet.
I think that this method is one of various ideas.
Problem When the map is embeded to a cell on spreadsheet as an image, the function =IMAGE() is suitable for this situation. However, setFormula() for importing =IMAGE() and DriveApp.createFile() for creating images from maps also cannot be used for custom functions.
Solution In order to avoid these limitations, I used Web Apps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
