<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - SOUWA_GAS - Effects on Optimized Codes of Pyramid Method</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&#xA;Kanshi TANAIKE&#xA;&lt;/center&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ref1&#34;&gt;I have already reported that the pyramid method is one of very effectively algolithms for summing string elements in an array using Google Apps Script (GAS).&lt;/a&gt; This report describes the adaptability of the pyramid method to any languages except for GAS. c++ (g++), Go, Java, Javascript on Node.js, Python and Ruby were chosen as the sample languages. In those languages, there are languages which have the distinctive commands for summing the array elements. In this report, &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator as a standard command and a special command for each language were used. For c++ (g++), Javascript on Node.js and Python which have no distinctive commands for summing the array elements, only &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator was used. For others, both &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator and each special command such as &amp;ldquo;[]byte&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;StringBuilder&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;&amp;laquo;&amp;rdquo; were used. For languages without the distinctive commands for summing, the pyramid method made us show some interesting phenomena. It was found that the pyramid method shows a good effect on only the specific language. It was found that &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator had been optimized for g++ and Node.js. &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator of Python was corresponding to theoretical results. This means that &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; operator of Python is not optimized. On the other hand, for languages with the distinctive commands for summing, it was found that the distinctive commands is incompatible to the pyramid method. These results made us show the possibility of visualization for the optimized codes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
