<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>report on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in report on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:13:14 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recursive Knowledge Crystallization: A Framework for Persistent Autonomous Agent Self-Evolution</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/21/recursive-knowledge-crystallization-a-framework-for-persistent-autonomous-agent-self-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 16:13:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/21/recursive-knowledge-crystallization-a-framework-for-persistent-autonomous-agent-self-evolution/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract In the development of autonomous agents using Large Language Models (LLMs), restrictions such as context window limits and session fragmentation pose significant barriers to the long-term accumulation of knowledge. This study proposes a &amp;ldquo;self-evolving framework&amp;rdquo; where an agent continuously records and refines its operational guidelines and technical knowledge—referred to as its SKILL—directly onto a local filesystem in a universally readable format (Markdown). By conducting experiments across two distinct environments featuring opaque constraints and complex legacy server rules using Google&amp;rsquo;s Antigravity and Gemini CLI, we demonstrate the efficacy of this framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Major Update: Taking Advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/24/major-update-taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:26:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/24/major-update-taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Description I am thrilled to announce a significant update to the Taking Advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script repository! Now at Version 2.0.0, this comprehensive guide has been extensively revised and expanded to provide unparalleled insights and practical guidance for developers leveraging Google Apps Script Web Apps.
This major overhaul introduces a wealth of new and enhanced content, designed to empower you with a deeper understanding and more advanced capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trend of google-apps-script Tag on Stackoverflow in first half of 2023</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/06/06/trend-of-google-apps-script-tag-on-stackoverflow-in-first-half-of-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 09:51:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/06/06/trend-of-google-apps-script-tag-on-stackoverflow-in-first-half-of-2023/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Recently, I felt a change like never before in the questions on Stackoverflow. In order to confirm this, in this report, the trend of &amp;ldquo;google-apps-script&amp;rdquo; tag on Stackoverflow in the first half (January 1st to June 1st) of 2023 has been investigated. From this report, in 2023 when the affection of COVID-19 has been reduced socially, the appreciable trend was confirmed to the questions including a tag of &amp;ldquo;google-apps-script&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My report has been published on the Blog of Google Cloud</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/10/03/my-report-has-been-published-on-the-blog-of-google-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 15:18:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/10/03/my-report-has-been-published-on-the-blog-of-google-cloud/</guid>
      <description>My report has been published on the Blog of Google Cloud.
Blog Efficient File Management using Batch Requests with Google Apps Script

Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report: Recent Value of ScriptApp.getService().getUrl() in Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/06/11/report-recent-value-of-scriptapp.getservice.geturl-in-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 09:52:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/06/11/report-recent-value-of-scriptapp.getservice.geturl-in-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>There is a method of ScriptApp.getService().getUrl() for obtaining the Web Apps URL in Google Apps Script.
  Before the V8 runtime is released, this method had returned the endpoint like https://script.google.com/macros/s/{deploymentId}/exec.
  After the V8 runtime was released, the endpoint of https://script.google.com/macros/s/{deploymentId}/dev was returned.
  Now, it seems that this returns https://script.google.com/macros/s/###/exec.
  But, in the current stage, when I access this endpoint, the message of Sorry, unable to open the file at this time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
