<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NodeTips on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/nodetips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NodeTips on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:38:13 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/nodetips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gemini CLI Extension: FileSearchStore-extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/gemini-cli-extension-filesearchstore-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:38:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/gemini-cli-extension-filesearchstore-extension/</guid>
      <description>Here introduces a new Gemini CLI extension that integrates Google&amp;rsquo;s File Search feature. This tool establishes a fully managed Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system directly on the command line.
The extension is designed to simplify the use of the Gemini API&amp;rsquo;s File Search, a powerful new feature that enables RAG grounded in personal or proprietary knowledge bases. While the underlying API requires scripting, this Node.js-built CLI extension allows users to seamlessly manage File Search stores and generate context-aware content grounded in their private documents without having to leave the terminal interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating File Search with the Gemini CLI Extension</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/integrating-file-search-with-the-gemini-cli-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:27:12 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/11/integrating-file-search-with-the-gemini-cli-extension/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a Gemini CLI extension that integrates Google&amp;rsquo;s File Search feature. This tool provides a fully managed Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) system directly in your command line, enabling content generation grounded in your private documents and data.
Introduction The Gemini API recently introduced File Search, a powerful feature that enables Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) using your own documents as a knowledge base. This allows you to generate content grounded in personal or proprietary information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
