<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Image on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/image/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Image on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 09:55:47 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/image/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Text to Image for Google Document using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/20/replacing-text-to-image-for-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 09:55:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/20/replacing-text-to-image-for-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>[Gists]()
This is a sample script for replacing text to image for Google Document using Google Apps Script (GAS). There is a method for replacing text to text at Class Text of DocumentApp. But there are not methods for replacing text to image. So I created this sample script.
Demo : This sample image was created by k3-studio.
Usage : replaceTextToImage(body, replaceText, image, width);   body : body of document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitation of Images for Inserting to Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/10/limitation-of-images-for-inserting-to-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 08:51:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/10/limitation-of-images-for-inserting-to-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Introduction Here I would like to introduce about the limitation of images for inserting to Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script (GAS). When you want to insert the images to Spreadsheet using GAS, insertImage() of class Sheet is usually used for this situation. At this time, an error sometimes occurs. This indicates that there is the limitation for inserting images to Spreadsheet. So I investigated the limitation.
As a result, it was found that the limitation depends on the image area (pixels^2) rather than the file size of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ImgApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/20/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 15:11:32 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/20/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</guid>
      <description>ImgApp was updated to v1.2.0. New method was added.
3. updateThumbnail() Overview This method is for updating thumbnail of files on Google Drive using images you selected.
Description For example, zip files don&amp;rsquo;t have the thumbnail on Google Drive. An icon is shown as the thumbnail. For the most files, Google Drive can create automatically each thumbnail. But there are sometimes files which cannot be created the thumbnail. Zip file is also one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Images on Spreadsheet</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/21/retrieving-images-on-spreadsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 08:27:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/21/retrieving-images-on-spreadsheet/</guid>
      <description>Gist
This is a sample script for retrieving images on Spreadsheet.
Unfortunately, there are no methods for retrieving directly images on spreadsheet using GAS. So I use the method which retrieves URL from =image(URL) and retrieves the image from the URL.
In this case, =image(URL) has to be in the cell. Images embedded by insertImage() cannot be retrieved.
At first, please confirm them.
Sample script : var cell = &amp;quot;A1&amp;quot;; // Cell address with the function of &amp;quot;=image()&amp;quot; var filename = &amp;quot;samplename&amp;quot;; // Output filename var image = SpreadsheetApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ImgApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/29/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 16:09:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/29/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</guid>
      <description>ImgApp was updated to v1.1.0. New method was added.
2. doResize() Overview This method is for resizing images.
Description Unfortunately, there are no methods to resize images at Google Apps Script. As a workaround, there is a method that it imports the image in Google Document and resizes the image using setWidth() and setHeight(). But in this method, the resized blob cannot be retrieved. So although I had thought of other workaround, I had not been able to find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - ImgApp - getSize()</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/27/gas-library---imgapp---getsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 16:21:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/27/gas-library---imgapp---getsize/</guid>
      <description>1. getSize() Overview This method is for retrieving the width and height of image as the unit of pixel.
Description Unfortunately, there are no methods to directly retrieve the image size at Google Apps Script. As a workaround, there is a method that it imports the image in Google Document and retrieves the size using getWidth() and getHeight(). But in this method, it uses much time and resources on Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - CreateImg</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/17/gas-library---createimg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:29:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/17/gas-library---createimg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had been looking for creating an image from coordinate data. Unfortunately I have never found them. So I made this. This Google Apps Script (GAS) library creates an image file from coordinate data.
You can see the detail information at https://github.com/tanaikech/CreateImg.
There is a part where I would like to improve in this library. That&amp;rsquo;s convByteSlice(). I think that there is the method to be faster about the part.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>