<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cli on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cli on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:43:21 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - gorearrange</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/10/15/cli-tool---gorearrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 16:43:21 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/10/15/cli-tool---gorearrange/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to interactively rearrange a text data on a terminal.
Description Since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find CLI tools for manually rearranging text data, I created this CLI tool.
For this, at first, I created a Golang library go-rearrange.
The detail information and how to get this are https://github.com/tanaikech/gorearrange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v131</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/15/updated-ggsrun-to-v131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 10:12:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/15/updated-ggsrun-to-v131/</guid>
      <description>ggsrun was updated to v.1.3.1  Recently, when scripts on local PC is uploaded to Google Drive as a new project, the time to create on Google became a bit long. (I think that this is due to Google Update.) Under this situation, when the script is uploaded, the timeout error occurs while the new project is created using the script. So the time until timeout of fetch was modified from 10 seconds to 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v130</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/30/updated-ggsrun-to-v130/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:08:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/30/updated-ggsrun-to-v130/</guid>
      <description>ggsrun was updated to v.1.3.0  From this version, container-bound scripts can be downloaded. The container-bound script is the script created at the script editor on Google Sheets, Docs, or Forms file.  In order to download container-bound scripts, the project ID of container-bound scripts is required. The project ID can be retrieved as follows.  Open the project. And please operate follows using click.  -&amp;gt; File -&amp;gt; Project properties -&amp;gt; Get Script ID (This is the project ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v122</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/12/updated-ggsrun-to-v122/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 14:31:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/12/updated-ggsrun-to-v122/</guid>
      <description>ggsrun was updated to v.1.2.2  For Google Docs (spreadsheet, document, slide and drawing), since I noticed that the revision files would not be able to be retrieved using Drive API v3, I modified this using new workaround.  The new workaround is to use Drive API v2. drive.revisions.get of Drive API v2 can retrieve not only the revision list, but also the export links. I thought of the use of the export links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - gislack</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/30/updated-cli-tool---gislack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:40:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/30/updated-cli-tool---gislack/</guid>
      <description>gislack is a CLI tool to submit files to both Gist and Slack.
 v1.0.1 (June 30, 2017)  Some modifications related to error handling.   Please check it out. https://github.com/tanaikech/gislack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - gislack</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/cli-tool---gislack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 12:59:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/cli-tool---gislack/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to submit files to both Gist and Slack.
Description When I discuss about developing scripts, I often use Slack. When I submitted a script to Slack, I had saved the script to Gist as a backup. I had done manually this on my browser. Namely, I wanted to be saving the revision of script while I&amp;rsquo;m discussing about the script at Slack. Recently, I wished this process had been able to be automatically run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - goris</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/13/updated-cli-tool---goris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 10:28:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/13/updated-cli-tool---goris/</guid>
      <description>goris is a CLI tool to search for images with Google Reverse Image Search.
Today, it was updated to v1.1.0. Please check it out. https://github.com/tanaikech/goris
When images are matched to a searched image, web pages with matching images are retrieved. These are web pages displayed on Google top page. When this is not used, images are retrieved. This was added as a boolean option. (This was added by a request.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v121</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/28/updated-ggsrun-to-v121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 14:20:08 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/28/updated-ggsrun-to-v121/</guid>
      <description>ggsrun was updated to v.1.2.1  Configuration file (ggsrun.cfg) became to be able to be read using the environment variable.  You can check this at here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v120</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/19/updated-ggsrun-to-v120/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 08:49:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/19/updated-ggsrun-to-v120/</guid>
      <description>ggsrun was updated to v.1.2.0  Added a command for retrieving revision files on Google Drive. Some modifications.  You can check this at here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - goris</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/16/updated-cli-tool---goris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 12:56:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/16/updated-cli-tool---goris/</guid>
      <description>goris is a CLI tool to search for images with Google Reverse Image Search.
Today, it was updated to v1.0.1. Please check it out. https://github.com/tanaikech/goris
When number of retrieved URLs is smaller than number of default output, an error had occurred. This was fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - gogauth</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/09/updated-cli-tool---gogauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 09:00:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/09/updated-cli-tool---gogauth/</guid>
      <description>gogauth is a CLI tool to easily retrieve access token for using APIs on Google.
I thought that if the access token can easily retrieve, it may be useful for users who can use various convenience Google APIs. So I created this. Also this can be used for testing sample script like the demo. If this will be helpful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.
Today, it was updated to v2.0.1. Please check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated ggsrun to v110</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/30/updated-ggsrun-to-v110/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 11:49:35 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/30/updated-ggsrun-to-v110/</guid>
      <description>Updated ggsrun to v.1.1.0 Added a command for updating existing project on Google Drive. One of scripts in the project can be also updated.
https://github.com/tanaikech/ggsrun</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - goris</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/26/cli-tool---goris/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 16:52:10 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/26/cli-tool---goris/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to search for images with Google Reverse Image Search.
Motivation Because I had wanted to search for images with an image URL and file on my terminal, I created this. This can download images from searched image URLs.
The detail information and how to get this are https://github.com/tanaikech/goris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - ggsrun</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/24/cli-tool---ggsrun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 15:07:11 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/24/cli-tool---ggsrun/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a CLI tool to execute Google Apps Script (GAS) on a terminal.
Motivation Will you want to develop GAS using CoffeeScript on your local PC? Generally, when we develop GAS, we have to login to Google using own browser and develop it using Javascript on the Script Editor. Recently, I have wanted to have more convenient local-environment for developing GAS. So I created this &amp;ldquo;ggsrun&amp;rdquo;.
The detail information and how to get this are https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: CLI Tool - gogauth</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/19/updated-cli-tool---gogauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 13:34:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/19/updated-cli-tool---gogauth/</guid>
      <description>gogauth is a CLI tool to retrieve easily access token for using APIs on Google.
Today, it was updated with big changes. Please check it out.
https://github.com/tanaikech/gogauth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Tool - gogauth</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/02/24/cli-tool---gogauth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 12:29:32 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/02/24/cli-tool---gogauth/</guid>
      <description>Released a CLI tool for easily retrieving accesstoken from Google OAuth2. The title is gogauth. When I have seen stackoverflow, I knew that it is difficult to retrieve accesstoken from Google OAuth2. So I made this.
Features of this CLI tool are as follows.
 Retrieves easily accesstoken from Google OAuth2 for using Drive API.
 If you have PhantomeJS, this retrieves &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; from Google using it. So you don&amp;rsquo;t need to launch your browser for retrieving &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>