<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavascriptTips on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/javascripttips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavascriptTips on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 13:21:25 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/javascripttips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Processing Duplicated Rows of 2 Dimensional Arrays using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/05/17/processing-duplicated-rows-of-2-dimensional-arrays-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 13:21:25 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/05/17/processing-duplicated-rows-of-2-dimensional-arrays-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/5c2d6187c08b2d7b2f7a561de0c75c5e&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are sample scripts for processing the duplicated rows of 2 dimensional arrays using Google Apps Script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I use Google Spreadsheet and/or see Stackoverflow, I sometimes see the situation which is required to process the duplicated rows of 2 dimensional arrays. I thought that when the sample scripts for it have already prepared, they will be useful for other users including me. So I published this post. This sample scripts can be also used for Javascript. If this post is useful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upload Files to Google Drive using Javascript</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/13/upload-files-to-google-drive-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:16:54 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/13/upload-files-to-google-drive-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/bd53b366aedef70e35a35f449c51eced&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanaikech/ResumableUploadForGoogleDrive_js&#34;&gt;At October 11, 2019, I published a Javascript library to to run the resumable upload for Google Drive.&lt;/a&gt; When this is used, the large file can be uploaded. You can also use this js library.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a sample script for uploading files to Google Drive using Javascript. The files are uploaded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/drive/api/v3/reference/&#34;&gt;Drive API v3&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code&gt;gapi.client.drive.files.create()&lt;/code&gt; can create an empty file on Google Drive. But it cannot directly upload files including contents. I think that this might not be able to upload files and metadata with the multipart/related, although this might be resolved by the future update. So now, as one of workarounds, I use using XMLHttpRequest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing Values by Checking Duplicated Values of JSON for Javascript</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/21/changing-values-by-checking-duplicated-values-of-json-for-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 08:30:37 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/21/changing-values-by-checking-duplicated-values-of-json-for-javascript/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/4c659fbb7cf8df0bc2c063dafa10e36c&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This sample script is for changing values by checking duplicated values of JSON for Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the following script. There is an array with a JSON data with 3 keys and 3 values. It is found that the values for each element duplicate. These duplicated values are changing by adding numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use this for managing filenames. This script also can be used for Google Apps Script. If this was useful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
