<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Library on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/library/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Library on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 15:11:32 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/library/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ImgApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/20/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 15:11:32 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/20/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</guid>
      <description>ImgApp was updated to v1.2.0. New method was added.
3. updateThumbnail() Overview This method is for updating thumbnail of files on Google Drive using images you selected.
Description For example, zip files don&amp;rsquo;t have the thumbnail on Google Drive. An icon is shown as the thumbnail. For the most files, Google Drive can create automatically each thumbnail. But there are sometimes files which cannot be created the thumbnail. Zip file is also one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - OnedriveApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/16/gas-library---onedriveapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 10:31:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/16/gas-library---onedriveapp/</guid>
      <description>This is a library of Google Apps Script for using Microsoft OneDrive.
Feature This library can carry out following functions using OneDrive APIs.
 Retrieve file list on OneDrive. Delete files and folders on OneDrive. Create folder on OneDrive. Download files from OneDrive to Google Drive. Upload files from Google Drive to OneDrive.  Demo You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/OnedriveApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ImgApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/29/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 16:09:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/29/updated-gas-library---imgapp/</guid>
      <description>ImgApp was updated to v1.1.0. New method was added.
2. doResize() Overview This method is for resizing images.
Description Unfortunately, there are no methods to resize images at Google Apps Script. As a workaround, there is a method that it imports the image in Google Document and resizes the image using setWidth() and setHeight(). But in this method, the resized blob cannot be retrieved. So although I had thought of other workaround, I had not been able to find it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - ImgApp - getSize()</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/27/gas-library---imgapp---getsize/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 16:21:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/27/gas-library---imgapp---getsize/</guid>
      <description>1. getSize() Overview This method is for retrieving the width and height of image as the unit of pixel.
Description Unfortunately, there are no methods to directly retrieve the image size at Google Apps Script. As a workaround, there is a method that it imports the image in Google Document and retrieves the size using getWidth() and getHeight(). But in this method, it uses much time and resources on Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Library - getcode</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/21/go-library---getcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 14:17:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/21/go-library---getcode/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a Golang library to automatically get an authorization code for retrieving access token using OAuth2.
Description When it retrieves an access token and refresh token using OAuth2, the code for retrieving them has to be got by authorization on own browser. In order to retrieve the code, in generally, users have to click the authorization button and copy the code on the browser. This library can be automatically got the code by launching HTML server as a redirected server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - SOUWA</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/19/updated-gas-library---souwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 07:06:45 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/19/updated-gas-library---souwa/</guid>
      <description>SOUWA means summing in Japanese. SOUWA can sum string elements in an array at the high speed. The speed of SOUWA with the pyramid algorithm is about 380 times faster than that of the standard method. New algorithm for summing array elements was developed for SOUWA. You can see the detailed report of this library at here. If you are interested in this, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.
It was updated to v1.0.2. Please check it out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - CreateImg</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/17/gas-library---createimg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:29:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/04/17/gas-library---createimg/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had been looking for creating an image from coordinate data. Unfortunately I have never found them. So I made this. This Google Apps Script (GAS) library creates an image file from coordinate data.
You can see the detail information at https://github.com/tanaikech/CreateImg.
There is a part where I would like to improve in this library. That&amp;rsquo;s convByteSlice(). I think that there is the method to be faster about the part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Library - souwapy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library---souwapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 13:38:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library---souwapy/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;ldquo;souwapy&amp;rdquo; is a library for summing array elements with high speed by new algorithm (Pyramid method). The speed is faster than csv and panbdas module of python and v8 engine of node.js. The souwapy module is 2.3 and 3.1 times faster than csv and pandas module, respectively. This was really surprised me. It was found that the theory was correct.
At first, I have created this theory for Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - SOUWA_GAS - Effects on Optimized Codes of Pyramid Method</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library---souwa_gas---effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library---souwa_gas---effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</guid>
      <description>Kanshi TANAIKE 
Abstract I have already reported that the pyramid method is one of very effectively algolithms for summing string elements in an array using Google Apps Script (GAS). This report describes the adaptability of the pyramid method to any languages except for GAS. c++ (g++), Go, Java, Javascript on Node.js, Python and Ruby were chosen as the sample languages. In those languages, there are languages which have the distinctive commands for summing the array elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>