<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>form on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/form/</link>
    <description>Recent content in form on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 10:02:05 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/form/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Report: Easily Implementing HTML Form with Google Spreadsheet as Database using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/31/report-easily-implementing-html-form-with-google-spreadsheet-as-database-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 10:02:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/31/report-easily-implementing-html-form-with-google-spreadsheet-as-database-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report introduces the method for easily implementing HTML forms with a Google Spreadsheet as a database using Google Apps Script. There are 2 patterns for the HTML form using Google Apps Script. One is that an HTML form is put into the same Google Apps Script project. Another is that an HTML form is put to a different server from a Google Apps Script project. In this report, the methods for easily implementing both patterns are introduced using the sample scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - HtmlFormApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/29/updated-gas-library-htmlformapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 10:23:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/05/29/updated-gas-library-htmlformapp/</guid>
      <description>HtmlFormApp was updated to v1.0.1.   v1.0.1 (May 29, 2023)
 When multiple files are uploaded, each URL was set as the hyperlink.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/HtmlFormApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening and Closing Google Forms on Time using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/01/18/opening-and-closing-google-forms-on-time-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 14:09:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/01/18/opening-and-closing-google-forms-on-time-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for opening and closing Google Forms on time using Google Apps Script.
In order to test this sample script, please do the following flow.
Usage 1. Create a new Google Form. Please create a new Google Form and set your sample questions. And, please open the script editor of Google Form.
2. Prepare sample script. Please copy and paste the following script to the script editor of Google Form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report: Rule of Item IDs for Questions of Google Forms</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/09/02/report-rule-of-item-ids-for-questions-of-google-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:29:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/09/02/report-rule-of-item-ids-for-questions-of-google-forms/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a report related to the rule of item IDs for questions of Google Forms.
When the questions are created using the method of batchUpdate with Google Forms API, the created questions have the item IDs when the item IDs are not given in the request body. ( https://developers.google.com/forms/api/reference/rest/v1/forms#item ) For example, when you want to create a question and update the created question in one API call, it is required to include the custom item ID in the request body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Responses from Grid Items of Google Form using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/28/analyzing-responses-from-grid-items-of-google-form-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:55:11 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/28/analyzing-responses-from-grid-items-of-google-form-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for analyzing the responses from Grid Items of Google Form using Google Apps Script.
In this sample situation, all responses are retrieved from Grid Items of Google Form, and the average values of each row of each question are calculated. And, the result is put on the Spreadsheet.
Sample situation Input: Sample Google Form The sample Google Form is as follows.
Output: Sample Spreadsheet The sample output is as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Quizzes in Google Form using Google Forms Service with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/05/creating-quizzes-in-google-form-using-google-forms-service-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 09:25:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/05/creating-quizzes-in-google-form-using-google-forms-service-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for creating quizzes in Google Form using Google Forms Service with Google Apps Script.
Usage 1. Prepare questions and answers. In this sample, the questions and answers are prepared using Spreadsheet as follows.
2. Sample script. This script is container-bound script of the above Spreadsheet.
function myFunction() {  const formTitle = &amp;#34;sample&amp;#34;; // This is a form title.  const sheetName = &amp;#34;Sheet1&amp;#34;; // This is a sheet name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Quizzes in Google Form using Google Forms API with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/04/creating-quizzes-in-google-form-using-google-forms-api-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 17:48:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/04/04/creating-quizzes-in-google-form-using-google-forms-api-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for creating quizzes in Google Form using Google Forms API with Google Apps Script. Recently, Google Forms API has been officially published, and it got to be able to be used by users. By this, quizzes in Google Form can be created using Google Forms API.
Here, there is one thing that can be achieved by Google Forms API. When Google Forms API is used, each choice in each question can be shuffled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, Google Forms API has been officially released as version 1</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/03/17/finally-google-forms-api-has-been-officially-released-as-version-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 10:59:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/03/17/finally-google-forms-api-has-been-officially-released-as-version-1/</guid>
      <description>Finally, Google Forms API has been officially released as version 1.
 Create surveys, quizzes, and more using the Google Forms API, now generally available
  The Google Forms API provides programmatic access for managing Google Forms and acting on responses— empowering developers to build powerful integrations on top of Forms.
 Forms API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - HtmlFormApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/02/01/gas-library-htmlformapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 13:35:21 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/02/01/gas-library-htmlformapp/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a Google Apps Script library for parsing the form object from HTML form and appending the submitted values to the Spreadsheet.
Description There is Google Form in the Google service. Google Form can parse the submitted data and put it in the Spreadsheet. But when we want to use the custom form, it is required to use the HTML form on Web Apps, dialog, and sidebar. In this case, it is required to prepare Javascript and Google Apps Script for parsing the form object from the HTML form and appending the parsed values to Spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Javascript library - HtmlFormObjectParserForGoogleAppsScript_js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/01/11/update-javascript-library-htmlformobjectparserforgoogleappsscript_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 17:00:21 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/01/11/update-javascript-library-htmlformobjectparserforgoogleappsscript_js/</guid>
      <description>This is a Javascript library for sending the HTML form object to Google Apps Script using google.script.run.
HtmlFormObjectParserForGoogleAppsScript_js was updated to v1.0.1.
  v1.0.1 (January 11, 2022)
 A new argument of includeOrder was added as the 4th argument. This library returns the parsed form object as a JSON object. By this, the order of HTML form object is not saved. From this version, this order can be included. This argument includes the order of each input tag in form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Google Forms API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/10/16/announcing-the-google-forms-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 20:11:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/10/16/announcing-the-google-forms-api/</guid>
      <description>Announcing the Google Forms API  Google is proud to announce the Google Forms API! The Forms API is currently available in Restricted Beta, with Open Beta expected to follow in Q4.
 Forms API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting All Response Values from Google Form to Google Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/10/15/putting-all-response-values-from-google-form-to-google-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 13:54:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/10/15/putting-all-response-values-from-google-form-to-google-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for putting all response values from Google Form to Google Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script.
Sample script Please copy and paste the following script to the script editor of Google Spreadsheet and set the variables of formId and sheetName.
function myFunction() {  const formId = &amp;#34;###&amp;#34;; // Please set the Google Form ID.  const sheetName = &amp;#34;Sheet1&amp;#34;; // Please set the sheet name of sheet you want to put the values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directly Submitting Answers to Google Form using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/27/directly-submitting-answers-to-google-form-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 09:33:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/27/directly-submitting-answers-to-google-form-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for directly submitting answers to Google Form using Google Apps Script.
The sample Google Form is as follows.
For this Google Form, this sample script submits the values of sample text, option2 and option1, option2, sample option to Google Form.
Sample script For the multiple answers, it seems that it is required to send the values as the query parameter. I thought that the same key is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark: Concurrent Writing to Google Spreadsheet using Form</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/15/benchmark-concurrent-writing-to-google-spreadsheet-using-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 14:42:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/15/benchmark-concurrent-writing-to-google-spreadsheet-using-form/</guid>
      <description>Gists
  Published: September 15, 2021
  Updated: September 17, 2021
 From the discussions, added data by changing the wait time of LockService for Web Apps.    Kanshi Tanaike
Introduction When the users try to write to a Spreadsheet using a form, the developers have to consider the concurrent submission from the form. For example, when multiple users submit the data with the form simultaneously, all data are possibly not to be saved to the Spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript library - HtmlFormObjectParserForGoogleAppsScript_js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/02/13/javascript-library-htmlformobjectparserforgoogleappsscript_js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:11:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/02/13/javascript-library-htmlformobjectparserforgoogleappsscript_js/</guid>
      <description>Parser for Sending HTML Form Object to Google Apps Script using google.script.run Overview This is a Javascript library for sending the HTML form object to Google Apps Script using google.script.run.
Description HTML form object is parsed by this library, and the object can be sent to Google Apps Script using google.script.run. After the V8 runtime got to be able to be used for Google Apps Script, when the file input tag is included in the HTML form object, the object sent to Google Apps Script using google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Values Submitted from HTML Form using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/09/04/using-values-submitted-from-html-form-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:58:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/09/04/using-values-submitted-from-html-form-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for using the values submitted from the HTML form using Google Apps Script and Javascript. In this case, the values include the files.
Issue &amp;lt;form&amp;gt;  Text: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;#34;text&amp;#34; name=&amp;#34;sampleText1&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  Single file: &amp;lt;input type=&amp;#34;file&amp;#34; name=&amp;#34;sampleFile1&amp;#34; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;input  type=&amp;#34;submit&amp;#34;  name=&amp;#34;button&amp;#34;  value=&amp;#34;submit&amp;#34;  onclick=&amp;#34;main(this.parentNode)&amp;#34;  /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/form&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;  function main(e) {  google.script.run.sample(e);  } &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; This is a simple sample script for sending the values of form to Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
