<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upload on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/upload/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upload on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:16:54 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/upload/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Files to Google Drive using Javascript</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/13/upload-files-to-google-drive-using-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 10:16:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/13/upload-files-to-google-drive-using-javascript/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading files to Google Drive using Javascript. The files are uploaded by Drive API v3. gapi.client.drive.files.create() can create an empty file on Google Drive. But it cannot directly upload files including contents. I think that this might not be able to upload files and metadata with the multipart/related, although this might be resolved by the future update. So now, as one of workarounds, I use using XMLHttpRequest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Files From Local To Google Drive by Python without Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/12/uploading-files-from-local-to-google-drive-by-python-without-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 11:39:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/12/uploading-files-from-local-to-google-drive-by-python-without-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading files from local PC to Google Drive using Python. In this sample, Quickstart is not used. So when you use this script, please retrieve access token.
Curl sample : curl -X POST \ -H &amp;quot;Authorization: Bearer ### access token ###&amp;quot; \ -F &amp;quot;metadata={name : &#39;sample.png&#39;, parents: [&#39;### folder ID ###&#39;]};type=application/json;charset=UTF-8&amp;quot; \ -F &amp;quot;file=@sample.png;type=image/png&amp;quot; \ &amp;quot;https://www.googleapis.com/upload/drive/v3/files?uploadType=multipart&amp;quot;  ]
Python sample : When above curl sample is converted to Python, it becomes as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Local Files to Google Drive without Authorization using HTML Form</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/11/06/uploading-local-files-to-google-drive-without-authorization-using-html-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 08:54:37 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/11/06/uploading-local-files-to-google-drive-without-authorization-using-html-form/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading local file to Google Drive without the authorization using HTML form. A selected file in your local PC using HTML form is uploaded to Google Drive and saved to Google Drive.
When you use this, at first, please deploy Web Apps. The script is doPost() of following scripts.
Script : Google Apps Script function doPost(e) { var data = Utilities.base64Decode(e.parameters.data); var blob = Utilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading CSV File as Spreadsheet and Modifying Permissions using Golang</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/21/uploading-csv-file-as-spreadsheet-and-modifying-permissions-using-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 15:43:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/21/uploading-csv-file-as-spreadsheet-and-modifying-permissions-using-golang/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for uploading CSV file as Spreadsheet and modifying permissions using Golang.
I think that the detail information of google-api-go-client is a bit little. The sample scripts are so little. It retrieves most information from only godoc and GitHub. So I publish such sample scripts here. If this is useful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.
Important points :  Give mimeType of file that it wants to upload to options of Media(r io.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Image Files to Slack Using Incoming Webhooks by Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/07/uploading-image-files-to-slack-using-incoming-webhooks-by-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 12:37:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/07/uploading-image-files-to-slack-using-incoming-webhooks-by-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gist
This sample script is for uploading image files to Slack using Incoming Webhooks by Google Apps Script.
When users try to upload image files to Slack using Incoming Webhooks, it has been known that although the access token is required to directly upload them, Incoming Webhooks can upload them by using the tag of image_url. In this sample script, it uploads image files (BMP, GIF, JPEG and PNG) on Google Drive to Slack using Incoming Webhooks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Files to OneDrive Using Node.js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/15/uploading-files-to-onedrive-using-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 10:00:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/15/uploading-files-to-onedrive-using-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Upload contents for an item on OneDrive In order to use this script, please retrieve client id, client secret and refresh token before. About this, you can see the detail information at https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/d9674f0ead7e3320c5e3184f5d1b05cc.
1. Simple item upload This is for the simple item upload is available for items with less than 4 MB of content. The detail information is https://dev.onedrive.com/items/upload_put.htm.
var fs = require(&#39;fs&#39;); var mime = require(&#39;mime&#39;); var request = require(&#39;request&#39;); var file = &#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>