<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2UI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2ui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2UI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:19:16 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2ui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bringing A2UI to Google Workspace with Gemini</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/19/bringing-a2ui-to-google-workspace-with-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:19:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/19/bringing-a2ui-to-google-workspace-with-gemini/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article explores implementing the Agent-to-User Interface (A2UI) protocol within Google Apps Script. It demonstrates utilizing Gemini&amp;rsquo;s structured output to render secure, dynamic, server-driven UIs—like booking forms and event lists—directly inside Google Sheets, streamlining workflows without complex external infrastructure.
Introduction I recently published a sample implementation demonstrating how to bring the Agent-to-User Interface (A2UI) concepts to Google Apps Script (GAS). Ref
A2UI is an emerging open-standard protocol designed to enable AI agents to generate rich, interactive user interfaces that render natively across web, mobile, and desktop environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A2UI for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/08/a2ui-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:38:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/08/a2ui-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to implement Google&amp;rsquo;s A2UI (Agent-to-User Interface) using Google Apps Script (GAS). By porting official Python/TypeScript examples to GAS, we show how to create dynamic, AI-generated interfaces within Google Workspace, enabling flexible business automation and interactive user experiences without complex server infrastructure.
Introduction Google recently released A2UI, a protocol designed for agent-driven interfaces. Ref A2UI enables AI agents to generate rich, interactive user interfaces that render natively across web, mobile, and desktop environments without executing arbitrary code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
