<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A2UI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2ui/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A2UI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:11:42 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/a2ui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Adaptive Learning Agents with A2UI, Gemini, and Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/07/building-adaptive-learning-agents-with-a2ui-gemini-and-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 11:11:42 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/07/building-adaptive-learning-agents-with-a2ui-gemini-and-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/0f26de9e861353ef95caa8ec50411087&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20260207a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article demonstrates how to build an adaptive learning agent using Agent-to-User Interface (A2UI), Gemini, and Google Apps Script. We explore a system that generates personalized quizzes, tracks performance in Google Sheets, and dynamically adjusts difficulty to maximize learning efficiency within the Google Workspace ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A2UI (Agent-to-User Interface) represents a paradigm shift in how users interact with generative AI. Originally open-sourced by Google and implemented in TypeScript and Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/A2UI&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;, A2UI becomes even more powerful when integrated with Google Apps Script (GAS). This combination enables seamless access to the Google Workspace ecosystem, transforming static documents into intelligent, agentic applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Chatbots: Building Task-Driven Agentic Interfaces in Google Workspace with A2UI and Gemini</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/03/beyond-chatbots-building-task-driven-agentic-interfaces-in-google-workspace-with-a2ui-and-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:50:21 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/02/03/beyond-chatbots-building-task-driven-agentic-interfaces-in-google-workspace-with-a2ui-and-gemini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/3ca39a750381aaf4f0c19c75fe71ff8d&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20260203a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explores A2UI (Agent-to-User Interface) using Google Apps Script and Gemini. By generating dynamic HTML via structured JSON, Gemini transforms Workspace into an &amp;ldquo;Agent Hub.&amp;rdquo; This recursive UI loop enables complex workflows where the AI builds the specific functional tools required to execute tasks directly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-the-evolution-of-ai-interaction&#34;&gt;Introduction: The Evolution of AI Interaction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/A2UI&#34;&gt;Official A2UI framework&lt;/a&gt; by Google marks a significant paradigm shift in how we interact with artificial intelligence. Short for &lt;strong&gt;Agent-to-User Interface&lt;/strong&gt;, A2UI represents the evolution of Large Language Models (LLMs) from passive chatbots into active agents capable of designing their own functional interfaces. Building upon my previous research, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/a2ui-for-google-apps-script-bcd0f37a3774&#34;&gt;A2UI for Google Apps Script&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/bringing-a2ui-to-google-workspace-with-gemini-0d85026969b8&#34;&gt;Bringing A2UI to Google Workspace with Gemini&lt;/a&gt;, I have refined this integration to support sophisticated, stateful workflows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing A2UI to Google Workspace with Gemini</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/19/bringing-a2ui-to-google-workspace-with-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:19:16 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/19/bringing-a2ui-to-google-workspace-with-gemini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/cb98c1df4874d82d8f6c0f015c7ff8d3&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20260119a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article explores implementing the Agent-to-User Interface (A2UI) protocol within Google Apps Script. It demonstrates utilizing Gemini&amp;rsquo;s structured output to render secure, dynamic, server-driven UIs—like booking forms and event lists—directly inside Google Sheets, streamlining workflows without complex external infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently published a sample implementation demonstrating how to bring the Agent-to-User Interface (A2UI) concepts to Google Apps Script (GAS). &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/google-cloud/a2ui-for-google-apps-script-bcd0f37a3774&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A2UI is an emerging open-standard protocol designed to enable AI agents to generate rich, interactive user interfaces that render natively across web, mobile, and desktop environments. &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.googleblog.com/introducing-a2ui-an-open-project-for-agent-driven-interfaces/&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; Unlike traditional approaches that often require executing arbitrary, high-risk code to generate UI on the fly, A2UI leverages a strict schema-based data format to describe UI components. This &amp;ldquo;secure-by-design&amp;rdquo; architecture effectively mitigates security risks like Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) while ensuring high performance and cross-platform consistency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A2UI for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/08/a2ui-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 15:38:17 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2026/01/08/a2ui-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/3960bee635dc5b80333588d27bb70936&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20260108a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article demonstrates how to implement Google&amp;rsquo;s A2UI (Agent-to-User Interface) using Google Apps Script (GAS). By porting official Python/TypeScript examples to GAS, we show how to create dynamic, AI-generated interfaces within Google Workspace, enabling flexible business automation and interactive user experiences without complex server infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google recently released &lt;strong&gt;A2UI&lt;/strong&gt;, a protocol designed for agent-driven interfaces. &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.googleblog.com/introducing-a2ui-an-open-project-for-agent-driven-interfaces/&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; A2UI enables AI agents to generate rich, interactive user interfaces that render natively across web, mobile, and desktop environments without executing arbitrary code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
