<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>download on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/download/</link>
    <description>Recent content in download on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 17:24:41 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/download/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - DownloadLargeFilesByUrl</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/08/01/updated-gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 17:24:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/08/01/updated-gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</guid>
      <description>v1.0.3 (August 1, 2020)
 When the file size less than the default chunk is downloaded, an error occurred. This bug was removed.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/DownloadLargeFilesByUrl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Time Download for Google Drive</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/04/one-time-download-for-google-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 11:59:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/10/04/one-time-download-for-google-drive/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a sample script for downloading files from Google Drive by the one time download method.
Description When you download a file from Google Drive, in generally, the login and the access token are required. If you want to download the file without the authorization for the simple situation, the file is required to be publicly shared. But the file might not be able to be shared publicly, because of various reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - DownloadLargeFilesByUrl</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/12/05/updated-gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 15:44:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/12/05/updated-gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</guid>
      <description>v1.0.1 (December 5, 2018)
 When the filename have not been retrieved, an error have occurred. This bug was removed.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/DownloadLargeFilesByUrl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - DownloadLargeFilesByUrl</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/09/02/gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 10:54:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/09/02/gas-library-downloadlargefilesbyurl/</guid>
      <description>Overview DownloadLargeFilesByUrl is a GAS library for downloading large files from URL to Google Drive using Google Apps Script (GAS).
Description I had been thinking of about whether a large file from an URL can be downloaded to Google Drive using GAS. When I have tried to download such large files, I noticed the following limitations. These limitations are due to the specification of GAS.
 When users download a file from URL using GAS, at the most users, it retrieves the blob using UrlFetchApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading File Using Button of Dialog Box on Google Docs</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/07/downloading-file-using-button-of-dialog-box-on-google-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 08:43:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/07/downloading-file-using-button-of-dialog-box-on-google-docs/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for downloading a file using a button of dialog box on Google Docs (Spreadsheet, Document and Slides).
Please use this sample script at script editor on Google Docs (Spreadsheet, Document and Slides). And please set file ID in the script.
FLow : The flow of this sample script is as follows.
 Run dialog().  Open a dialog.   When users click a download button, retrieve file ID at GAS side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Files Under Specific Folder using Node.js</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/17/downloading-files-under-specific-folder-using-node.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 09:25:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/17/downloading-files-under-specific-folder-using-node.js/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for downloading files under a specific folder using Node.js. It can download files with Google Docs and others.
This sample supposes as follows. So please confirm it.
 quickstart is used and default quickstart works fine.  In order to use this sample, please carry out as follows.
 Replace listFiles() of the default quickstart to this sample. Set folderid. This script can retrieve files in the folder with folderid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Shared Files on Google Drive Using Curl</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/05/downloading-shared-files-on-google-drive-using-curl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 11:06:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/05/downloading-shared-files-on-google-drive-using-curl/</guid>
      <description>Gists
When the shared files on Google Drive is downloaded, it is necessary to change the download method by the file size. The boundary of file size when the method is changed is about 40MB.
File size &amp;lt; 40MB CURL filename=&amp;#34;### filename ###&amp;#34;fileid=&amp;#34;### file ID ###&amp;#34;curl -L -o ${filename} &amp;#34;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;amp;id=${fileid}&amp;#34;File size &amp;gt; 40MB When it tries to download the file with more than 40MB, Google says to download from following URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Files From Google Drive Under No Authorization Using Browser</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/04/downloading-files-from-google-drive-under-no-authorization-using-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/04/downloading-files-from-google-drive-under-no-authorization-using-browser/</guid>
      <description>Gist
This is a sample script for downloading files from Google Drive under no authorization using browser. By using this sample, you can make other users download files from your Google Drive. Even if the other users are not Google users, they can download the files.
Demo This is a demonstration for downloading files from Google Drive under no authorization using browser. From the top document, You can see that an user who is not owner of Google Drive is downloading files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>