<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:00:51 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Time Information in Gemini and Current Time Handling</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/06/importance-of-time-information-in-gemini-and-current-time-handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:00:51 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/06/06/importance-of-time-information-in-gemini-and-current-time-handling/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report investigates how Gemini handles current time information, particularly when using the Gemini API. We found that while the Gemini web interface knows the current time, the Gemini API does not inherently. Therefore, applications must explicitly provide current time information in API calls for accurate time-sensitive responses.
Introduction The rapidly advancing field of generative AI is enabling increasingly complex tasks, particularly through the use of open protocols like the Model Context Protocol (MCP) and Agent2Agent (A2A) Protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Transfer: MCP Server (Web Apps/Google Apps Script) to MCP Client (Gemini/Python)</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/10/image-transfer-mcp-server-web-apps/google-apps-script-to-mcp-client-gemini/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 14:06:39 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/10/image-transfer-mcp-server-web-apps/google-apps-script-to-mcp-client-gemini/python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report details transferring image data via Model Context Protocol (MCP) from Google Apps Script server to a Python/Gemini client, extending capabilities for multimodal applications beyond text.
Introduction Following up on my previous report, &amp;ldquo;Building Model Context Protocol (MCP) Server with Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo; (Ref), which detailed the transfer of text data between the MCP server and client, this new report focuses on extending the protocol to handle image data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Google Apps Script from Stackoverflow</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/01/analyzing-google-apps-script-from-stackoverflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:48:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/01/analyzing-google-apps-script-from-stackoverflow/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract The report details a novel Gemini API method to analyze big data beyond AI context window limits, which was validated with Stack Overflow data for insights into Google Apps Script&amp;rsquo;s potential.
Introduction Generative AI models face significant limitations when processing massive datasets, primarily due to the constraints imposed by their fixed context windows. Current methods thus struggle to analyze the entirety of big data within a single API call, preventing comprehensive analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Big Data Processing with Gemini</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/01/comprehensive-big-data-processing-with-gemini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 14:12:05 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/05/01/comprehensive-big-data-processing-with-gemini/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Generative AI faces limits in processing massive datasets due to context windows. Current methods can&amp;rsquo;t analyze entire data lakes. This report presents a Gemini API approach for comprehensive big data analysis beyond typical model limits.
Introduction The rapid advancement and widespread adoption of generative AI have been remarkable. High expectations are placed on these technologies, particularly regarding processing speed and the capacity to handle vast amounts of data. While AI processing speed continues to increase with technological progress, effectively managing and analyzing truly large datasets presents significant challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stowage Planning Automation Using Gemini: A Feasibility Study and A Prompt-Based Approach</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/04/03/stowage-planning-automation-using-gemini-a-feasibility-study-and-a-prompt-based-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 11:14:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/04/03/stowage-planning-automation-using-gemini-a-feasibility-study-and-a-prompt-based-approach/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Gemini 2.5 Pro Experimental enabled automated cargo ship stowage planning via prompt engineering, overcoming prior model limitations. This eliminates the need for complex algorithms, demonstrating AI&amp;rsquo;s potential in logistics.
Introduction Recently, I encountered a practical business challenge: automating stowage planning through AI. Specifically, I received a request to generate optimal container loading plans for cargo ships, a task traditionally requiring significant manual effort and domain expertise. In initial tests, prior to the release of Gemini 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo Function Calling for Gemini API Through Prompt Engineering</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/10/01/pseudo-function-calling-for-gemini-api-through-prompt-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 10:39:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/10/01/pseudo-function-calling-for-gemini-api-through-prompt-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This research explores &amp;ldquo;pseudo function calling&amp;rdquo; in Gemini API using prompt engineering with JSON schema, bypassing model dependency limitations.
Introduction Large Language Models (LLMs) like Gemini and ChatGPT offer powerful functionalities, but their capabilities can be further extended through function calling. This feature allows the LLM to execute pre-defined functions with arguments generated based on the user&amp;rsquo;s prompt. This unlocks a wide range of applications, as demonstrated in these resources (see References).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gemini API with JSON schema</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/05/07/gemini-api-with-json-schema/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 16:33:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/05/07/gemini-api-with-json-schema/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Overview These are sample scripts in Python and Node.js for controlling the output format of the Gemini API using JSON schemas.
Description In a previous report, &amp;ldquo;Taming the Wild Output: Effective Control of Gemini API Response Formats with response_mime_type,&amp;rdquo; I presented sample scripts created with Google Apps Script. Ref Following its publication, I received requests for sample scripts using Python and Node.js. This report addresses those requests by providing sample scripts in both languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crafting Bespoke Output Formats with Gemini API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/03/25/crafting-bespoke-output-formats-with-gemini-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:54:26 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/03/25/crafting-bespoke-output-formats-with-gemini-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract The Gemini API unlocks potential for diverse applications but requires consistent output formatting. This report proposes a method using question phrasing and API calls to craft a bespoke output, enabling seamless integration with user applications. Examples include data categorization and obtaining multiple response options.
Introduction With the release of the LLM model Gemini as an API on Vertex AI and Google AI Studio, a world of possibilities has opened up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executing Google Apps Script with Service Account</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/10/19/executing-google-apps-script-with-service-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 14:59:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/10/19/executing-google-apps-script-with-service-account/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract One day, you might have a situation where it is required to run Google Apps Script using the service account. Unfortunately, in the current stage, Google Apps Script cannot be directly run with the service account because of the current specification. So, this report introduces a workaround for executing Google Apps Script using the service account.
Introduction When you want to execute Google Apps Script from outside of Google, as the basic approach, it can be achieved by Google Apps Script API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Download of File from Google Drive using Drive API with Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/28/resumable-download-of-file-from-google-drive-using-drive-api-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 11:58:23 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/28/resumable-download-of-file-from-google-drive-using-drive-api-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for achieving the resumable download of a file from Google Drive using Dive API with Python.
There might be a case in that you want to achieve the resumable download of a file from Google Drive using Dive API with Python. For example, when a large file is downloaded, the downloading might be stopped in the middle of downloading. At that time, you might want to resume the download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Until Expiration Time of Access Token Retrieved By googleapis for Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/16/using-until-expiration-time-of-access-token-retrieved-by-googleapis-for-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 15:05:58 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/16/using-until-expiration-time-of-access-token-retrieved-by-googleapis-for-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
When Google APIs are used with googleapis for Python, the client is obtained as follows.
creds = service_account.Credentials.from_service_account_file(service_account_credential_file, scopes=scopes) service = build(&amp;#34;drive&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;v3&amp;#34;, credentials=creds) In this case, when the script is run, the access token is retrieved every time. But, the expiration time of the retrieved access token is 1 hour. Here, there might be the case that you want to use the access token until the expiration time. It is considered that effectively using the access token will lead to SDGs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Access Token from Service Account using oauth2client and google-auth with Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/15/retrieving-access-token-from-service-account-using-oauth2client-and-google-auth-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 14:46:18 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/02/15/retrieving-access-token-from-service-account-using-oauth2client-and-google-auth-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for retrieving the access token from the service account using oauth2client and google-auth with Python.
Sample script 1 Use oauth2client.
from oauth2client.service_account import ServiceAccountCredentials  SERVICE_ACCOUNT_FILE = &amp;#34;credentials.json&amp;#34; SCOPES = [&amp;#34;https://www.googleapis.com/auth/drive&amp;#34;]  creds = ServiceAccountCredentials.from_json_keyfile_name(SERVICE_ACCOUNT_FILE, scopes=SCOPES) res = creds.get_access_token() access_token = res.access_token  print(access_token) Sample script 2 Use google-auth. In the current stage, this method might be general.
from google.oauth2 import service_account import google.auth.transport.requests  SERVICE_ACCOUNT_FILE = &amp;#34;credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Files to Google Drive with Asynchronous Process using Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/05/28/uploading-files-to-google-drive-with-asynchronous-process-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:45:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2022/05/28/uploading-files-to-google-drive-with-asynchronous-process-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading files to Google Drive with asynchronous process using Python.
Sample script import aiohttp import asyncio import json  folder_id = &amp;#34;###&amp;#34; # Please set the folder ID you want to put. token = &amp;#34;###&amp;#34; # Please set your access token. url = &amp;#34;https://www.googleapis.com/upload/drive/v3/files&amp;#34;   async def workers(file):   async with aiohttp.ClientSession() as session:  metadata = {&amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: file[&amp;#34;filename&amp;#34;], &amp;#34;parents&amp;#34;: [folder_id]}  data = aiohttp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Template Texts with Array in Google Document using Docs API with Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/25/replacing-template-texts-with-array-in-google-document-using-docs-api-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 10:51:57 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2021/09/25/replacing-template-texts-with-array-in-google-document-using-docs-api-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for replacing the template texts with an array in Google Document using Docs API with Python.
The sample input and output situations are as follows.
In the current stage, when replaceAllText of Docs API is used with the sample value of [&amp;quot;updated text 1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;updated text 2&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;updated text 3&amp;quot;], all values of {{oldText}} are replaced with the 1st value of updated text 1 in one batch request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sample Scripts for Creating New Event with Google Meet Link to Google Calendar using Various Languages</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 16:04:18 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/12/03/sample-scripts-for-creating-new-event-with-google-meet-link-to-google-calendar-using-various-languages/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages. When I saw the official document of &amp;ldquo;Add video and phone conferences to events&amp;rdquo;, in the current stage, I can see only the sample script for Javascript. But I saw the several questions related to this for various languages. So I published the sample scripts for creating new event with Google Meet link to Google Calendar using various languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving All Values from All Sheets from URL of 2PACX- of Web Published Google Spreadsheet using Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/10/13/retrieving-all-values-from-all-sheets-from-url-of-2pacx-of-web-published-google-spreadsheet-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 14:59:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/10/13/retrieving-all-values-from-all-sheets-from-url-of-2pacx-of-web-published-google-spreadsheet-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for retrieving all values from all sheets from URL of 2PACX- of Web Published Google Spreadsheet using Python.
In this post, it supposes that the Google Spreadsheet has already been published for Web. Ref
Flow The flow of this method is as follows.
 Retrieve XLSX data from the URL of web published Google Spreadsheet as BytesIO data.  The URL is like https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-###/pubhtml.   XLSX data is parsed with openpyxl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: python library - getfilelistpy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/08/11/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 11:19:36 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/08/11/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</guid>
      <description>python library - getfilelistpy was updated to v1.0.7.   v1.0.7 (August 11, 2020)
 Pull request was reflected.    You can check getfilelistpy at https://github.com/tanaikech/getfilelistpy.
You can also check getfilelistpy at https://pypi.org/project/getfilelistpy/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GetFileList for golang, Javascript, Node.js and Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/01/updated-getfilelist-for-golang-javascript-node.js-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 14:12:33 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/01/updated-getfilelist-for-golang-javascript-node.js-and-python/</guid>
      <description>Updated: GetFileList for golang, Javascript, Node.js and Python
This is the libraries to retrieve the file list with the folder tree from the specific folder of own Google Drive and shared Drives.
 Golang: https://github.com/tanaikech/go-getfilelist  Updated to v1.0.4.   Javascript: https://github.com/tanaikech/GetFileList_js  Updated to v1.0.3.   Node.js: https://github.com/tanaikech/node-getfilelist  Updated to v1.0.5.   Python: https://github.com/tanaikech/getfilelistpy  Updated to v1.0.6.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: python library - getfilelistpy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/05/15/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 11:49:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/05/15/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</guid>
      <description>python library - getfilelistpy was updated to v1.0.5.   v1.0.5 (May 15, 2020)
  Shared drive got to be able to be used. The file list can be retrieved from both your Google Drive and the shared drive.
 For example, when the folder ID in the shared Drive is used id of resource, you can retrieve the file list from the folder in the shared Drive.      You can check getfilelistpy at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Script of Resumable Upload with Google Drive API for Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 14:10:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/05/simple-script-of-resumable-upload-with-google-drive-api-for-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a simple sample script for achieving the resumable upload to Google Drive using Python. In order to achieve the resumable upload, at first, it is required to retrieve the location, which is the endpoint of upload. The location is included in the response headers. After the location was retrieved, the file can be uploaded to the location URL.
In this sample, a PNG file is uploaded with the resumable upload using a single chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libraries of gdoctableapp for golang, Node.js and python were updated to v110</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/22/libraries-of-gdoctableapp-for-golang-node.js-and-python-were-updated-to-v110/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 15:22:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/22/libraries-of-gdoctableapp-for-golang-node.js-and-python-were-updated-to-v110/</guid>
      <description>Libraries of gdoctableapp for golang, Node.js and python were updated to v1.1.0   go-gdoctableapp
 v1.1.0 (January 22, 2020)  2 new methods were added. From this version, the texts can be replaced by images. The direct link and local file can be used as the image.      node-gdoctableapp
 v1.1.0 (January 22, 2020)  New method was added. From this version, the texts can be replaced by images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libraries of gdoctableapp for golang, Node.js and python were updated to v105</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/21/libraries-of-gdoctableapp-for-golang-node.js-and-python-were-updated-to-v105/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 15:00:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/01/21/libraries-of-gdoctableapp-for-golang-node.js-and-python-were-updated-to-v105/</guid>
      <description>Libraries of gdoctableapp for golang, Node.js and python were updated to v1.0.5  go-gdoctableapp node-gdoctableapp gdoctableapppy  Update History   v1.0.5 (January 21, 2020)
 When the inline objects and tables are put in the table. An error occurred. This bug was removed by this update.    I got the pull request at here.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: python library - getfilelistpy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/23/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 15:20:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/08/23/updated-python-library-getfilelistpy/</guid>
      <description>python library - getfilelistpy was updated to v1.0.4.   v1.0.4 (August 23, 2019)
 For OAuth2, oauth2client and google_auth_oauthlib got to be able to be used. About the sample script for google_auth_oauthlib, please see this.    You can check getfilelistpy at https://github.com/tanaikech/getfilelistpy.
You can also check getfilelistpy at https://pypi.org/project/getfilelistpy/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Table to Google Document by Retrieving Values from Google Spreadsheet for Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/21/creating-a-table-to-google-document-by-retrieving-values-from-google-spreadsheet-for-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 14:27:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/21/creating-a-table-to-google-document-by-retrieving-values-from-google-spreadsheet-for-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for creating a table to Google Document by retrieving values from Google Spreadsheet for Python.
Before you use this script, please install python library of gdoctableapppy.
$ pip install gdoctableapppy Sample script: This sample script uses Service Account.
In this sample script, the values are retrieved from Sheet1!A1:C5 of Spreadsheet, and new table is created to the Document using the values.
from google.oauth2 import service_account from gdoctableapppy import gdoctableapp from googleapiclient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python library - gdoctableapppy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/18/python-library-gdoctableapppy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 11:46:31 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/07/18/python-library-gdoctableapppy/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a python library to manage the tables on Google Document using Google Docs API.
Description Google Docs API has been released. When I used this API, I found that it is very difficult for me to manage the tables on Google Document using Google Docs API. Although I checked the official document, unfortunately, I thought that it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult for me. So in order to easily manage the tables on Google Document, I created this library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python library - getfilelistpy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/11/17/python-library-getfilelistpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 15:11:04 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/11/17/python-library-getfilelistpy/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a python library to retrieve the file list with the folder tree from the specific folder of Google Drive.
Description When I create applications for using Google Drive, I often retrieve a file list from a folder in the application. So far, I had created the script for retrieving a file list from a folder for each application. Recently, I thought that if there is the script for retrieving the file list with the folder tree from the folder of Google Drive as a library, it will be useful for me and other users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Append Values by Inserting Rows using Google Sheets API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/27/append-values-by-inserting-rows-using-google-sheets-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:51:55 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/27/append-values-by-inserting-rows-using-google-sheets-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
In the case appending values to cell by inserting rows, when sheets.spreadsheets.values.append is used, the values are appended to the next empty row of the last row. If you want to append values to between cells with values by inserting row, you can achieve it using sheets.spreadsheets.batchUpdate.
When you use this, please use your access token.
Endpoint : POST https://sheets.googleapis.com/v4/spreadsheets/### spreadsheet ID ###:batchUpdate Request body : In this request body, it appends the data of &amp;ldquo;sample1, sample2, sample3&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;A1:A3&amp;rdquo; of the sheetId of &amp;ldquo;1234567890&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Files From Local To Google Drive by Python without Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/12/uploading-files-from-local-to-google-drive-by-python-without-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 11:39:22 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/02/12/uploading-files-from-local-to-google-drive-by-python-without-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading files from local PC to Google Drive using Python. In this sample, Quickstart is not used. So when you use this script, please retrieve access token.
Curl sample : curl -X POST \  -H &amp;#34;Authorization: Bearer ### access token ###&amp;#34; \  -F &amp;#34;metadata={name : &amp;#39;sample.png&amp;#39;, parents: [&amp;#39;### folder ID ###&amp;#39;]};type=application/json;charset=UTF-8&amp;#34; \  -F &amp;#34;file=@sample.png;type=image/png&amp;#34; \  &amp;#34;https://www.googleapis.com/upload/drive/v3/files?uploadType=multipart&amp;#34; ]
Python sample : When above curl sample is converted to Python, it becomes as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Gmail Body with Japanese Language using Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/18/decoding-gmail-body-with-japanese-language-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 08:22:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/18/decoding-gmail-body-with-japanese-language-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Gist
This is a sample script for decoding Gmail body with Japanese language using Python.
msg = service.users().messages().get(userId=&amp;#39;me&amp;#39;, id=id).execute() parts = msg[&amp;#39;payload&amp;#39;][&amp;#39;parts&amp;#39;] for e in parts:  msg = base64.urlsafe_b64decode(e[&amp;#39;body&amp;#39;][&amp;#39;data&amp;#39;]).decode(&amp;#39;utf-8&amp;#39;).encode(&amp;#39;cp932&amp;#39;, &amp;#34;ignore&amp;#34;).decode(&amp;#39;cp932&amp;#39;)  print(msg) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Thumbnail of File on Google Drive using Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/19/updating-thumbnail-of-file-on-google-drive-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 16:27:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/19/updating-thumbnail-of-file-on-google-drive-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for updating thumbnail of file on Google Drive using Python.
This sample supposes that quickstart is used and default quickstart works fine. In order to use this sample, please carry out as follows.
 Replace main() of the default quickstart to this sample.  Script : import base64 # This is used for this sample.  def main():  credentials = get_credentials()  http = credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text Plugin - gislacks</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/sublime-text-plugin-gislacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 13:33:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/22/sublime-text-plugin-gislacks/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a plugin of Sublime Text 3 for submitting files to both Gist and Slack.
Description I like to use Sublime Text for developing scripts. And when I discuss about developing scripts, I often use Slack. When I submitted a script to Slack, I had saved the script to Gist as a backup. I had done manually this on my browser. Namely, I wanted to be saving the revision of script while I&amp;rsquo;m discussing about the script at Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Handling for Subprocess at Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/09/error-handling-for-subprocess-at-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 14:27:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/09/error-handling-for-subprocess-at-python/</guid>
      <description>This sample is for error handling for subprocess.Popen. It confirms whether the execution file is existing. If the execution file is also not in the path, the error message is shown.
import subprocess  res = subprocess.Popen(  &amp;#34;application&amp;#34;, # &amp;lt;- Execution file  stdout=subprocess.PIPE,  stderr=subprocess.PIPE,  shell=True ).communicate()  if len(res[1]) == 0:  print(&amp;#34;ok: Application is existing.&amp;#34;) else:  print(&amp;#34;Error: Application is not found.&amp;#34;) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Constructor Between Classes at Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/09/using-constructor-between-classes-at-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 10:52:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/06/09/using-constructor-between-classes-at-python/</guid>
      <description>This sample is for using constructor between classes at Python.
Sample : class test1:   def __init__(self):  self.msg = &amp;#34;sample text&amp;#34;   class test2:   def __init__(self):  self.msg = test1().msg   print(test2().msg)  &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; sample text </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Transfer for Google Drive Without Authorization</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/10/file-transfer-for-google-drive-without-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 13:28:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/10/file-transfer-for-google-drive-without-authorization/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this article, I would like to introduce how to transfer files for Google Drive under no authorization.
This has also been published here. https://github.com/tanaikech/FileTransfer
Description When we download and upload files for Google Drive, it usually has to use Drive API. In order to use Drive API, access token is required. If you want to make your friends download and upload files for your Google Drive, the authorization process is to take time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCR using Google Drive API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/02/ocr-using-google-drive-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 14:21:55 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/02/ocr-using-google-drive-api/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample script for OCR using Google Drive API. A text file which converted by OCR can be retrieved by inputting an image file.
In this sample, Python Quickstart is used. The detail information is https://developers.google.com/drive/v3/web/quickstart/python. Please read “Step 1: Turn on the Drive API” and “Step 2: Install the Google Client Library”.
from __future__ import print_function import httplib2 import os import io  from apiclient import discovery from oauth2client import client from oauth2client import tools from oauth2client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting PDF to TXT</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/01/converting-pdf-to-txt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 15:04:30 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/05/01/converting-pdf-to-txt/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample script for converting a PDF file to a TXT file. 2 steps are required for this.
 Upload a PDF file as a Google Document Download a Google Document as a TXT file  In this sample, Python Quickstart is used. The detail information is https://developers.google.com/drive/v3/web/quickstart/python. Please read &amp;ldquo;Step 1: Turn on the Drive API&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Step 2: Install the Google Client Library&amp;rdquo;.
from __future__ import print_function import httplib2 import os import io  from apiclient import discovery from oauth2client import client from oauth2client import tools from oauth2client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download Files Without Authorization From Google Drive</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/03/20/download-files-without-authorization-from-google-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 14:30:15 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/03/20/download-files-without-authorization-from-google-drive/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this article, files can be downloaded without authorization.
Description When we download files from Google Drive, it usually has to use Drive API. In order to use Drive API, access token is required. If you want to make your friends download files from your Google Drive, the authorization process is to take time. Also Web Link for each files can be used. But it has to set for each files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Library - souwapy</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library-souwapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 13:38:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/30/python-library-souwapy/</guid>
      <description>This &amp;ldquo;souwapy&amp;rdquo; is a library for summing array elements with high speed by new algorithm (Pyramid method). The speed is faster than csv and panbdas module of python and v8 engine of node.js. The souwapy module is 2.3 and 3.1 times faster than csv and pandas module, respectively. This was really surprised me. It was found that the theory was correct.
At first, I have created this theory for Google Apps Script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Element&#39;s Duplicate Number in Array at Python</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/21/elements-duplicate-number-in-array-at-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 12:29:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/21/elements-duplicate-number-in-array-at-python/</guid>
      <description>Suddenly I had to need this.
This script can get the duplicate number of each element in array at Python. In this script, the duplicate number of each element is obtained and sorted by the duplicate number. This was expressed by the comprehension.
data = [&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;c&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;d&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;c&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;d&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;c&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;b&amp;#39;] result = sorted({i: data.count(i) for i in set(data)}.items(), key=lambda x: x[1], reverse=True) print(result) &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; [(&amp;#39;b&amp;#39;, 4), (&amp;#39;c&amp;#39;, 3), (&amp;#39;d&amp;#39;, 2), (&amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, 1)] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - SOUWA_GAS - Effects on Optimized Codes of Pyramid Method</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/gas-library-souwa_gas-effects-on-optimized-codes-of-pyramid-method/</guid>
      <description>Abstract I have already reported that the pyramid method is one of very effectively algolithms for summing string elements in an array using Google Apps Script (GAS). This report describes the adaptability of the pyramid method to any languages except for GAS. c++ (g++), Go, Java, Javascript on Node.js, Python and Ruby were chosen as the sample languages. In those languages, there are languages which have the distinctive commands for summing the array elements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
