<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Document on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/document/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Document on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 11:49:48 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/document/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Limitations for Inserting Images to Google Docs</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/05/limitations-for-inserting-images-to-google-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 11:49:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/05/limitations-for-inserting-images-to-google-docs/</guid>
      <description>Gists
When an image is inserted to Google Docs (Spreadsheet, Document and Slides) using the method of insertImage using Google Apps Script, there is the case that the error occurs. The error messages are &amp;ldquo;server error&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;invalid image data&amp;rdquo;. Here, I would like to introduce the limitations for inserting images to Google Docs. As the result, it was found that the limitation is due to both the mimeTypes and the area of image rather than the file size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting Positioned Images on Google Document using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/deleting-positioned-images-on-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:49:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/deleting-positioned-images-on-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for deleting the positioned images on Google Document using Google Apps Script. In the current stage, unfortunately, there are no methods for deleting the positioned images in Class PositionedImage, yet. But when Google Docs API is used, the positioned images can be deleted.
When you use this script, please enable Google Docs API at Advanced Google Services and API console. You can see how to enable them at here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modify Searched Text to Small Capital Letters using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/modify-searched-text-to-small-capital-letters-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 10:43:58 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/01/modify-searched-text-to-small-capital-letters-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for modifying the searched text to the small capital letters using Google Apps Script. Unfortunately, in the current stage, there are no methods for modifying the part of texts to the small capital letters in Document Service, yet. But when Google Docs API is used, this can be achieved.
When you use this script, please enable Google Docs API at Advanced Google Services and API console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modify Shading Color of Paragraph on Google Document using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/03/16/modify-shading-color-of-paragraph-on-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 16:25:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/03/16/modify-shading-color-of-paragraph-on-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a script for modifying the shading color of paragraph on Google Document using Google Apps Script.
Recently, by releasing Google Docs API, the shading color got to be able to be modified using the script. Here, I would like to introduce a sample script for modifying the shading color of the paragraph on Google Document. At the current Document Service, the shading color cannot be modified yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Text to Image for Google Document using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/20/replacing-text-to-image-for-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 09:55:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/08/20/replacing-text-to-image-for-google-document-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for replacing text to image for Google Document using Google Apps Script (GAS). There is a method for replacing text to text at Class Text of DocumentApp. But there are not methods for replacing text to image. So I created this sample script.
Demo : This sample image was created by k3-studio.
Usage : replaceTextToImage(body, replaceText, image, width);   body : body of document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Number of Lines of Google Document</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/09/retrieving-number-of-lines-of-google-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 09:02:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/07/09/retrieving-number-of-lines-of-google-document/</guid>
      <description>Gists
There are no prepared methods for retrieving the number of lines in the Google Document. So I thought this workaround. If the end of each line can be detected, the number of lines can be retrieved. So I tried to add the end markers of each line using OCR.
At Google Documents, when a sentence is over the page width, the sentence automatically has the line break. But the line break has no \r\n or \n.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>