<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>multipart on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/multipart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in multipart on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 11:00:07 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/multipart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Request of multipart/form-data with Simple Request Body using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/10/17/request-of-multipart/form-data-with-simple-request-body-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 11:00:07 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/10/17/request-of-multipart/form-data-with-simple-request-body-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script of the request of multipart/form-data with a simple request body using Google Apps Script. I hope that the users will easy to use Class UrlFetchApp by this report.
This report is the updated post of &amp;ldquo;Multipart-POST Request Using Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo;.
Description I had already reported about this at this report. In that case, it was required to create a bit complicated request body to request multipart/form-data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multipart-POST Request Using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/21/multipart-post-request-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 10:34:38 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/21/multipart-post-request-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gist
These sample scripts are for requesting multipart post using Google Apps Script.
In most cases, the multipart request is used for uploading files. So I prepared 2 sample situations as follows. For each situation, the request parameters are different.
 Upload a file from Google Drive to Slack. Convert an excel file to Spreadsheet on Google Drive using Drive API v3.  Multipart post is required for these situations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
