<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>process on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in process on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 15:05:47 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging GCP for Seamless Google Apps Script Log Export and Analysis with Gemini API</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/18/leveraging-gcp-for-seamless-google-apps-script-log-export-and-analysis-with-gemini-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 15:05:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/18/leveraging-gcp-for-seamless-google-apps-script-log-export-and-analysis-with-gemini-api/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Linking a Google Apps Script project to a GCP project enables you to export logs from the Class console to Logs Explorer for simplified analysis and debugging. By overcoming the limitations of in-script logging methods, this report outlines a method for exporting logs using the Cloud Logging API with Google Apps Script.
Introduction While developing applications with Google Apps Script, the Class console is a valuable tool for debugging individual components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Library - ProcessApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/02/10/updated-gas-library-processapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 11:04:42 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/02/10/updated-gas-library-processapp/</guid>
      <description>ProcessApp was updated to v1.0.1.
  v1.0.1 (February 10, 2019)
 New method of getExecutionTimeOfProcessType() was added.  This method retrieves the total execution time of all functions by filtering the process type. For example, the total execution time of Web Apps can be retrieved.      You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/ProcessApp</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAS Library - ProcessApp</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/02/09/gas-library-processapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 16:11:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/02/09/gas-library-processapp/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a library for retrieving the process and information of Google Apps Script.
Methods  getExecutionTimeOfTrigger() : This method retrieves the total execution time of all functions executed by the time-driven trigger at owner&amp;rsquo;s account. For example, you can know the total execution time of all functions executed by the time-driven trigger in 24 h. getDevUrl() : This method retrieves the endpoint of developer mode for Web Apps like https://script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
