<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Custom Function on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/custom-function/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Custom Function on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 14:20:27 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/topics/custom-function/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark: Measuring Process Costs for Formulas in Cells on Google Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/11/11/benchmark-measuring-process-costs-for-formulas-in-cells-on-google-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 14:20:27 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/11/11/benchmark-measuring-process-costs-for-formulas-in-cells-on-google-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/b00be25a02ec283689480ac8138cbfeb&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Google Spreadsheet is used, there is the case that the built-in functions and the custom functions in the cells are used. For the functions of Google Apps Script, there is the method for measuring the process cost. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanaikech/taking-advantage-of-google-apps-script#benchmarks&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; But for the built-in functions, it is required to create the script for it. In this report, the script for measuring a function put in a cell has been proposed, and the process cost of the built-in functions has been measured. The proposed script can measure the process cost for the built-in functions and custom functions on Google Spreadsheet. The script is created with using Google Apps Script. When the process cost can be known for the built-in functions and custom functions, it is considered that it will be useful for the developers using Google Spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
