<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Script Editor on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/script-editor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Script Editor on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:18:02 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/script-editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing HTML and Javascript Development in Script Editor of Google Apps Script: Overcoming Formatting Challenges</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/05/27/enhancing-html-and-javascript-development-in-script-editor-of-google-apps-script-overcoming-formatting-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:18:02 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/05/27/enhancing-html-and-javascript-development-in-script-editor-of-google-apps-script-overcoming-formatting-challenges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/be52daa21ccf07873ad2a2e43e566676&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20240527a/fig1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the improved Google Apps Script IDE launched in April 2022, challenges arise for HTML and Javascript development. The Script Editor&amp;rsquo;s built-in formatting for these languages proves insufficient, particularly for large Javascript codebases, potentially causing errors. This report proposes a solution to address this formatting issue and streamline development within the Script Editor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Google Apps Script Integrated Development Environment (IDE) Script Editor received a significant update on April 13, 2022, transforming it into a more modern and streamlined development experience. &lt;a href=&#34;https://workspaceupdates.googleblog.com/2022/04/apps-script-integrated-development-enviornment-improvements.html&#34;&gt;Ref&lt;/a&gt; This enhanced IDE empowers developers to create custom solutions that extend the capabilities of Google Workspace applications for their organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking Advantage of Auto-completion of Script Editor for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/09/17/taking-advantage-of-auto-completion-of-script-editor-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 09:41:37 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2023/09/17/taking-advantage-of-auto-completion-of-script-editor-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/b2f0461c1060b54d2edbd43733708f52&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tanaikech.github.io/image-storage/20230917a/fig1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a report for taking advantage of the auto-completion of the script editor for Google Apps Script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the current stage, the auto-completion is implemented in the script editor of Google Apps Script. This auto-completion can be used for not only the built-in classes and methods but also the methods for Javascript. This helps develop scripts and applications very much. In the case of the built-in classes and methods and the methods for Javascript, you can see the detailed specifications of the documents like &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/apps-script/reference&#34;&gt;the official documents&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference&#34;&gt;developer.mozilla.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Reformatted Scripts without Comments in a Project using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/28/retrieving-reformatted-scripts-without-comments-in-a-project-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 12:55:14 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/28/retrieving-reformatted-scripts-without-comments-in-a-project-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/tanaikech/61f69fd2ce181865d3430c260c6a5d0b&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a sample script for easily retrieving the reformatted scripts without comments in a project using Google Apps Script (GAS).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I create GAS script, if the format of script is not correct, the script editor lets me know about it. By this, I can find that the script editor and/or Google Drive checks the format of scripts. I had wished if I could use this function. Recently, I noticed an interesting function. A GAS project is created and when &lt;code&gt;function myFunction() {Logger.log(this)}&lt;/code&gt; is run in the script, I noticed that all scripts in the project are included in &lt;code&gt;this&lt;/code&gt;. Furthermore, when I saw the retrieved script, also I noticed that their scripts are reformatted and all comments are removed. In the case of Apps Script API, when the scripts are retrieved by the API, the retrieved script is the same to the original one. So I think that this will help users retrieve simply the reformatted GAS scripts, and such the reformatted scripts will be able to be used for the various situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
