<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>batch request on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/batch-request/</link>
    <description>Recent content in batch request on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 11:33:00 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/batch-request/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/15/google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 11:33:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/15/google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Overview These are the sample scripts of the batch requests for Drive API using Google Apps Script.
Description When we want to manage the files and folders on Google Drive, we have 2 ways. One is the use of Drive service. Another is the use of Drive API. In the case of them, when we want to manage a lot of files and folders, unfortunately, both ways have no batch requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing A Lot Of Google Calendar Events using Batch Requests with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/12/managing-a-lot-of-google-calendar-events-using-batch-requests-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 16:14:27 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/06/12/managing-a-lot-of-google-calendar-events-using-batch-requests-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is the sample scripts for managing a lot of Google Calendar Events using the batch requests with Google Apps Script.
Description When we want to manage the events of Google Calendar, we have 2 ways. One is the use of Calendar service. Another is the use of Calendar API. In the case of them, when we want to manage a lot of calendar events, unfortunately, both ways have no batch requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batching Requests for Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/01/19/batching-requests-for-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 09:38:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/01/19/batching-requests-for-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
There is the bathing requests in the Google APIs. The bathing requests can use the several API calls as a single HTTP request. By using this, for example, users can modify filenames of a lot of files on Google Drive. But there are limitations for the number of API calls which can process in one batch request. For example, Drive API can be used the maximum of 100 calls in one batch request.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>