<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DriveAPI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/driveapi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DriveAPI on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 16:48:25 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/driveapi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Which of Drive API v2 or v3 is used for DriveApp.searchFiles()</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/01/05/which-of-drive-api-v2-or-v3-is-used-for-driveapp.searchfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 16:48:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/01/05/which-of-drive-api-v2-or-v3-is-used-for-driveapp.searchfiles/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Experiment It has investigated the differences between the documents of &amp;ldquo;Search for Files&amp;rdquo; for v2 and v3. The following table shows the comparison of v2 and v3 for &amp;ldquo;Valid fields for files.list&amp;rdquo;. The column of DriveApp.searchFiles() means whether the query can be used for DriveApp.searchFiles().
   v2 v3 Difference DriveApp.searchFiles()     title name different v2: succeed, v3: fail   fullText fullText same    mimeType mimeType same    modifiedDate modifiedTime same    lastViewedByMeDate viewedByMeTime different v2: succeed, v3: fail   trashed trashed same    starred starred same    parents parents same    owners owners same    writers writers same    readers readers same    sharedWithMe sharedWithMe same    properties properties same    properties with visibility=&amp;lsquo;PRIVATE&amp;rsquo; appProperties different v2: succeed, v3: fail   visibility visibility same     Result As the result, it is considered that DriveApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Files with Filename Included Special Characters using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/07/retrieving-files-with-filename-included-special-characters-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 10:40:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/07/retrieving-files-with-filename-included-special-characters-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for retrieving files with filename included special characters using Google Apps Script. The files are used on Google Drive.
The files with filename of special characters cannot be retrieved using DriveApp.getFilesByName(). This workaround solved this.
As a query parameter, name contains &#39;filename with special characters&#39; is used. This contains is very important. name=&#39;filename with special characters&#39; cannot retrieve such files. Today, it was found that name contains &#39;filename with special characters&#39; is the workaround.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
