<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Convert on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/convert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Convert on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 11:14:59 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/convert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Many Files to Google Docs using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/11/converting-many-files-to-google-docs-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 11:14:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/04/11/converting-many-files-to-google-docs-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for converting a lot of files to Google Docs (Spreadsheet, Document and Slides).
 Batch request can be used for converting files. In this sample script, the files are converted using the batch request. Batch request can request 100 API by one API call. This sample script uses the fetchAll method. So even if there are over 100 files, this script can process them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Conversion from CSV File with Large Size (&gt; 50 MB) to Several Spreadsheets by Splitting File</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/06/26/resumable-conversion-from-csv-file-with-large-size--50-mb-to-several-spreadsheets-by-splitting-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 13:00:50 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/06/26/resumable-conversion-from-csv-file-with-large-size--50-mb-to-several-spreadsheets-by-splitting-file/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Overview This is a sample script which can achieve the resumable conversion from the large CSV-file to several spreadsheets by splitting the CSV file using Google Apps Script (GAS).
Description Is there a situation that you want to convert a CSV file with the large size (&amp;gt; 50 MB) to Spreadsheet? When such large CSV file is converted to Spreadsheet, you will experience the error. The reason is the size and/or also it may be due to the total cells (&amp;gt; 2,000,000 cells) of CSV file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading CSV File as Spreadsheet and Modifying Permissions using Golang</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/21/uploading-csv-file-as-spreadsheet-and-modifying-permissions-using-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 15:43:14 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/09/21/uploading-csv-file-as-spreadsheet-and-modifying-permissions-using-golang/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for uploading CSV file as Spreadsheet and modifying permissions using Golang.
I think that the detail information of google-api-go-client is a bit little. The sample scripts are so little. It retrieves most information from only godoc and GitHub. So I publish such sample scripts here. If this is useful for you, I&amp;rsquo;m glad.
Important points :  Give mimeType of file that it wants to upload to options of Media(r io.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interconversion Between Google Docs and Microsoft Docs</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/11/interconversion-between-google-docs-and-microsoft-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 15:02:37 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/08/11/interconversion-between-google-docs-and-microsoft-docs/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This sample script is for the interconversion between Google Docs (document, spreadsheet and presentation) and Microsoft Docs (word, excel and powerpoint). The feature is to convert them without Advanced Google Services.
Since Advanced Google Services is not used for this, if you publish your script with this script, you are not necessary to explain how to install Advanced Google Services. This script converts between Google Docs and Microsoft Docs using UrlFetchApp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>