<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>application on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in application on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:05:17 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Approach to Learning: Combining Gemini with Google Apps Script for Automated Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/08/a-novel-approach-to-learning-combining-gemini-with-google-apps-script-for-automated-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:05:17 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/08/a-novel-approach-to-learning-combining-gemini-with-google-apps-script-for-automated-qa/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This report proposes a novel learning method using Gemini to automate Q&amp;amp;A generation, addressing the challenges of manual Q&amp;amp;A creation. By integrating with Google tools, this approach aims to enhance learning efficiency, accessibility, and personalization while reducing costs.
Introduction Mastering a new subject often demands a significant time commitment. A proven strategy for efficient learning is through question-and-answer (Q&amp;amp;A) practice. This method typically involves constructing a dataset of pertinent Q&amp;amp;A pairs and subsequently engaging in repeated practice until desired proficiency levels are achieved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Application - UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/03/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 14:36:03 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/08/03/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</guid>
      <description>UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI was updated to v1.0.3.   v1.0.3 (August 3, 2024)
 On August 3, 2024, I upated GeminiWithFiles (https://github.com/tanaikech/GeminiWithFiles). In this version, PDF data can be processed with Gemini API without async/await. So, I updated UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI.    You can see the detail information here https://github.com/tanaikech/UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Application - UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/07/23/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 10:46:49 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/07/23/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</guid>
      <description>UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI was updated to v1.0.2.   v1.0.2 (July 23, 2024)
 On July 23, 2024, I noticed that PDF data could be directly parsed by Gemini API. It is considered that this is due to the update by the Google side. So, I updated setBlobs([blob], true) to setBlobs([blob], false) of the method parseInvoiceByGemini_. By this modification, the PDF blob is directly used with Gemini API. Ref    You can see the detail information here https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated: GAS Application - UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/17/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 14:37:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/17/updated-gas-application-unlocksmartinvoicemanagementwithgeminiapi/</guid>
      <description>UnlockSmartInvoiceManagementWithGeminiAPI was updated to v1.0.1.   v1.0.1 (June 17, 2024)
 In order to easily customize the value of &amp;ldquo;jsonSchema&amp;rdquo; for generating content with Gemini API, I added it as a new sheet of &amp;ldquo;jsonSchema&amp;rdquo; sheet in the Spreadsheet. When you customize it, you can edit the cell &amp;ldquo;A1&amp;rdquo; of the &amp;ldquo;jsonSchema&amp;rdquo; sheet. By this, the script generates content with Gemini API using your customized JSON schema. The cell &amp;ldquo;A2&amp;rdquo; is the number of characters of &amp;ldquo;A1&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Smart Invoice Management: Gemini, Gmail, and Google Apps Script Integration</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/15/unlock-smart-invoice-management-gemini-gmail-and-google-apps-script-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 14:58:45 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/15/unlock-smart-invoice-management-gemini-gmail-and-google-apps-script-integration/</guid>
      <description>Gists You can see the presentation of this application at https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dc2WPQkovZE. Abstract This report describes an invoice processing application built with Google Apps Script. It leverages Gemini, a large language model, to automatically parse invoices received as email attachments and automates the process using time-driven triggers. Introduction The emergence of large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and Gemini has significantly impacted various aspects of our daily lives. One such example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dining Reservation System using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/01/22/creating-dining-reservation-system-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 10:53:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/01/22/creating-dining-reservation-system-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Google Apps Script automates tasks (even offline) and builds web apps using spreadsheets as databases. This report presents a basic dining reservation system to illustrate key aspects of web app development with Apps Script, HTML, and Javascript.
Introduction Google Apps Script is one of the powerful automation tools for achieving the automation process. When Google Apps Script can be used for the situation, even when users are away from their computers, automation can continue thanks to cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
