<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>application on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in application on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 14:58:45 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Smart Invoice Management: Gemini, Gmail, and Google Apps Script Integration</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/15/unlock-smart-invoice-management-gemini-gmail-and-google-apps-script-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 14:58:45 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/06/15/unlock-smart-invoice-management-gemini-gmail-and-google-apps-script-integration/</guid>
      <description>Gists Abstract This report describes an invoice processing application built with Google Apps Script. It leverages Gemini, a large language model, to automatically parse invoices received as email attachments and automates the process using time-driven triggers. Introduction The emergence of large language models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and Gemini has significantly impacted various aspects of our daily lives. One such example is their ability to automate tasks previously requiring manual effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dining Reservation System using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/01/22/creating-dining-reservation-system-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 10:53:47 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2024/01/22/creating-dining-reservation-system-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Google Apps Script automates tasks (even offline) and builds web apps using spreadsheets as databases. This report presents a basic dining reservation system to illustrate key aspects of web app development with Apps Script, HTML, and Javascript.
Introduction Google Apps Script is one of the powerful automation tools for achieving the automation process. When Google Apps Script can be used for the situation, even when users are away from their computers, automation can continue thanks to cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
