<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webapps on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/webapps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webapps on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 10:42:46 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/webapps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update: Taking advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/01/16/update-taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 10:42:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/01/16/update-taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Taking advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script&amp;rdquo; was updated. A section of &amp;ldquo;How to use dev mode from outside&amp;rdquo; was added.
 When you deploy Web Apps, you can see the link labeled latest code. The link is like https://script.google.com/macros/s/###/dev. When you access to the link of latest code using your browser under you login to Google, you can access to Web Apps with the dev mode. But if you want to access to Web Apps with the dev mode from outside, there are no documents for the method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resumable Upload for Web Apps using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/17/resumable-upload-for-web-apps-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 16:48:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/05/17/resumable-upload-for-web-apps-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a sample script for uploading files with large size (&amp;gt; 50 MB) at Web Apps using Google Apps Script (GAS). The resumable upload method is used for uploading files. This script can be also applied to the script using gapi of javascript.
Demo This is a demonstration of this script. As a demonstration, it uploads a file with the size of 100 MB to my Google Drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/04/26/taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 08:35:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2018/04/26/taking-advantage-of-web-apps-with-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Overview This is a report to take advantage of Web Apps with Google Apps Script (GAS).
Description There is Web Apps as one of applications using Google Apps Script (GAS). I sometimes use this Web Apps. But I have only a little the information for the specification of Web Apps. So in order to take more advantage of Web Apps, I investigated and summarized about this. The aim of this report is to become one of the basic information for creating various applications using Web Apps with GAS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Local Files to Google Drive without Authorization using HTML Form</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/11/06/uploading-local-files-to-google-drive-without-authorization-using-html-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 08:54:37 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/11/06/uploading-local-files-to-google-drive-without-authorization-using-html-form/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for uploading local file to Google Drive without the authorization using HTML form. A selected file in your local PC using HTML form is uploaded to Google Drive and saved to Google Drive.
When you use this, at first, please deploy Web Apps. The script is doPost() of following scripts.
Script : Google Apps Script function doPost(e) { var data = Utilities.base64Decode(e.parameters.data); var blob = Utilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading Files From Google Drive Under No Authorization Using Browser</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/04/downloading-files-from-google-drive-under-no-authorization-using-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 15:57:20 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/07/04/downloading-files-from-google-drive-under-no-authorization-using-browser/</guid>
      <description>Gist
This is a sample script for downloading files from Google Drive under no authorization using browser. By using this sample, you can make other users download files from your Google Drive. Even if the other users are not Google users, they can download the files.

Demo This is a demonstration for downloading files from Google Drive under no authorization using browser. From the top document, You can see that an user who is not owner of Google Drive is downloading files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>