<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developer_tool on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/developer_tool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developer_tool on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:52:54 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/developer_tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fields Builder for Google APIs: Visualizing Partial Responses</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/23/fields-builder-for-google-apis-visualizing-partial-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:52:54 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/23/fields-builder-for-google-apis-visualizing-partial-responses/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract Fields Builder for Google APIs is a client-side web application that streamlines constructing the fields parameter. It parses Discovery documents into interactive trees, enabling developers to visually select nested resources, implement Partial Response, and optimize API payload sizes without manual syntax errors.
Introduction FieldsBuilderForGoogleAPIs is a specialized Web Application designed to streamline the construction of the fields parameter for Google APIs.
Since the update of the official Google API Explorer, developers have found it increasingly difficult to visually construct the fields parameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Apps: Fields Builder For Google APIs</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/04/web-apps-fields-builder-for-google-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 16:08:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2020/03/04/web-apps-fields-builder-for-google-apis/</guid>
      <description>Overview FieldsBuilderForGoogleAPIs is a Web Application for building the fields value for using Google APIs. This is mainly used for developing the scripts for using Google APIs.
Demo Description After the API explorer was updated, the fields of APIs cannot be created by the web interface. But it is important for using the fields property. Because when the fields property is used, only the required values can be retrieved. This leads to the low cost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
