<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithm on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithm on tanaike - Google Apps Script, Gemini API, and Developer Tips</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2026. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 14:39:34 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Improved Algorithms for Summation of Array Elements</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/improved-algorithms-for-summation-of-array-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 14:39:34 +0900</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2016/10/13/improved-algorithms-for-summation-of-array-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;center&gt;&#xA;Kanshi TANAIKE&#xA;&lt;/center&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I considered an efficient algorithm for summation of array elements. All elements in an array are string. When those elements are summed using scripts, a standard method is to add each element in order. If the script is run without any optimize, the process becomes gradually sluggish, because the total amount of active data during the summation process is proportional to the square of the number of array elements. This leads directly to the high process-cost. Such phenomenon notably appears at Google Apps Script (GAS). This report says about the solution of this problem using a new algorithm of a pyramid method. The pyramid method achieves that the total amount of active data increases proportional to the linear of the number of array elements. By this, the processing time becomes much shorter than that of the process using the standard method. The pyramid method achieved the process-cost reduction of $99.7%$ compared with the standard method at GAS. I realized again that new discoveries are hidden into the familiar scenes of every-day life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
