<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Custom Function on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/custom-function/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Custom Function on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 17:41:58 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/custom-function/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Value Putting by Custom Function of Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/06/02/fixing-value-putting-by-custom-function-of-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 17:41:58 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2019/06/02/fixing-value-putting-by-custom-function-of-spreadsheet-using-google-apps-script/</guid>
      <description>Gists
This is a sample script for fixing a value putting by a custom function of Spreadsheet using Google Apps Script. When a custom function is used, the value retrieved by the custom function of Spreadsheet is automatically updated by recalculating. So in the case that the value retrieved by the custom function is changed by the time, the value is also changed by automatically updating. In this sample script, I would like to introduce a method for fixing such values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Recalculation of Custom Function on Spreadsheet Part 1</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/23/automatic-recalculation-of-custom-function-on-spreadsheet-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 09:59:13 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2017/12/23/automatic-recalculation-of-custom-function-on-spreadsheet-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Gists
In this report, I would like to introduce a workaround for automatically recalculating custom functions on Spreadsheet.
1. Situation The sample situation is below. This is a sample situation for this document.
 There are 3 sheets with &amp;ldquo;sheet1&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;sheet2&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sheet3&amp;rdquo; of sheet name in a Spreadsheet. Calculate the summation of values of &amp;ldquo;A1&amp;rdquo; of each sheet using a custom function. Sample script of the custom function is as follows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>