<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antigravity on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/antigravity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antigravity on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:08:19 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/antigravity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Google Antigravity: Unlocking the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:08:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to integrate the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI with Google Antigravity. It addresses a Model Context Protocol (MCP) tool naming incompatibility using a custom proxy script, enabling seamless, authenticated automation of Google Workspace tasks directly within the Antigravity IDE environment.
Introduction Since its release, the Gemini CLI has been rapidly adopted across various development scenarios. Ref Its utility increased significantly with the introduction of Gemini CLI Extensions, which simplify the installation and management of Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Automation in Google Workspace: Bridging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:43:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article explores automating Google Workspace by integrating Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers. We demonstrate how to overcome tool limits and utilize custom extensions to enable AI agents to securely execute scripts, manage files, and perform RAG-based tasks using private data.
Introduction Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 are ushering in a new era of &amp;ldquo;Agent-First&amp;rdquo; development, transforming how we interact with cloud environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Generation Google Apps Script Development: Leveraging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:20:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates a cutting-edge workflow for Google Apps Script development using Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0. By integrating gas-fakes via the Model Context Protocol (MCP), we establish an environment where autonomous agents can generate, unit-test, and execute cloud-based scripts locally, revolutionizing the standard GAS development lifecycle.
Introduction Google Antigravity has officially been released. Ref This is a revolutionary &amp;ldquo;Agent-first&amp;rdquo; IDE powered by Gemini 3, designed to empower autonomous AI agents to plan, code, and verify tasks across the Editor, Terminal, and Browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
