<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antigravity on tanaike</title>
    <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/antigravity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antigravity on tanaike</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>ja</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:39:34 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanaikech.github.io/tags/antigravity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modularizing AI Agents: Integrating Google Apps Script Libraries with Gemini CLI and Antigravity</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/11/modularizing-ai-agents-integrating-google-apps-script-libraries-with-gemini-cli-and-antigravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:39:34 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/11/modularizing-ai-agents-integrating-google-apps-script-libraries-with-gemini-cli-and-antigravity/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article introduces a major update to gas-fakes enabling dynamic loading of Google Apps Script libraries. This enhancement allows developers to build modular, maintainable Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers. We demonstrate this by integrating sophisticated library-based tools with Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity for seamless Google Workspace automation.
Introduction I recently published an article titled &amp;ldquo;Power of Google Apps Script: Building MCP Server Tools for Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity in Google Workspace Automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power of Google Apps Script: Building MCP Server Tools for Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity in Google Workspace Automation</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/03/power-of-google-apps-script-building-mcp-server-tools-for-gemini-cli-and-google-antigravity-in-google-workspace-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:37:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/03/power-of-google-apps-script-building-mcp-server-tools-for-gemini-cli-and-google-antigravity-in-google-workspace-automation/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to build Model Context Protocol (MCP) tools directly using Google Apps Script. By leveraging the gas-fakes CLI, developers can execute Google Apps Script locally to automate Google Workspace via Gemini CLI and Google Antigravity, streamlining development and eliminating the overhead of dynamic tool creation.
Introduction With the rapid advancement of generative AI, ensuring the security of executing AI-generated scripts is of paramount importance to prevent arbitrary code execution vulnerabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Era for Google Apps Script: Unlocking the Future of Google Workspace Automation with Natural Language</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/01/a-new-era-for-google-apps-script-unlocking-the-future-of-google-workspace-automation-with-natural-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:19:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/12/01/a-new-era-for-google-apps-script-unlocking-the-future-of-google-workspace-automation-with-natural-language/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article redefines Google Apps Script (GAS) as a central integration hub in the AI era. It introduces the forefront of Google Workspace automation, realized through the fusion of the Model Context Protocol (MCP), Agent2Agent (A2A), and the Gemini CLI ecosystem. I cover everything from data integration bridging local and cloud environments (RAG) and sandbox technologies for safely executing AI-generated GAS, to the coordination of autonomous agents on the newly released Google Antigravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Google Antigravity: Unlocking the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:08:19 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/25/integrating-google-antigravity-unlocking-the-google-workspace-extension-for-gemini-cli/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates how to integrate the Google Workspace Extension for Gemini CLI with Google Antigravity. It addresses a Model Context Protocol (MCP) tool naming incompatibility using a custom proxy script, enabling seamless, authenticated automation of Google Workspace tasks directly within the Antigravity IDE environment.
Introduction Since its release, the Gemini CLI has been rapidly adopted across various development scenarios. Ref Its utility increased significantly with the introduction of Gemini CLI Extensions, which simplify the installation and management of Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Automation in Google Workspace: Bridging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:43:53 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/22/agentic-automation-in-google-workspace-bridging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article explores automating Google Workspace by integrating Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 with Model Context Protocol (MCP) servers. We demonstrate how to overcome tool limits and utilize custom extensions to enable AI agents to securely execute scripts, manage files, and perform RAG-based tasks using private data.
Introduction Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 are ushering in a new era of &amp;ldquo;Agent-First&amp;rdquo; development, transforming how we interact with cloud environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Generation Google Apps Script Development: Leveraging Antigravity and Gemini 3.0</title>
      <link>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:20:25 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanaikech.github.io/2025/11/21/next-generation-google-apps-script-development-leveraging-antigravity-and-gemini-3.0/</guid>
      <description>Gists
Abstract This article demonstrates a cutting-edge workflow for Google Apps Script development using Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0. By integrating gas-fakes via the Model Context Protocol (MCP), we establish an environment where autonomous agents can generate, unit-test, and execute cloud-based scripts locally, revolutionizing the standard GAS development lifecycle.
Introduction Google Antigravity has officially been released. Ref This is a revolutionary &amp;ldquo;Agent-first&amp;rdquo; IDE powered by Gemini 3, designed to empower autonomous AI agents to plan, code, and verify tasks across the Editor, Terminal, and Browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
